There is no audience here tonight in this hall at the National Constitution Center.
今晚在国家宪法中心的这个大厅里没有观众。
This is an intimate setting for two candidates who have never met.
这是一个适合两位从未见过面的候选人的亲密场合。
President Trump won the coin toss.
特朗普总统赢得了掷硬币的机会。
He chose to deliver the final closing statement of the evening.
他选择在今晚发表最后的总结发言。
Vice President Harris selected the podium to the right.
哈里斯副总统选择了右侧的讲台。
So let's now welcome the candidates to the stage.
现在让我们欢迎候选人上台。
Vice President Kamala Harris and President Donald Trump.
副总统卡马拉·哈里斯和总统唐纳德·特朗普。
Kamala Harris, let's have a good debate.
卡马拉·哈里斯，希望我们能进行一场精彩的辩论。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Welcome to you both.
欢迎你们二位。
It's wonderful to have you.
很高兴你们能在这里。
It's an honor to have you both here tonight.
今晚能有你们在这里，我感到非常荣幸。
Good evening.
晚上好。
We are looking forward to a spirited and thoughtful debate.
我们期待一场热烈而富有深度的辩论。
So let's get started.
那么，让我们开始吧。
I want to begin tonight with the issue that voters repeatedly say is their number one issue, and that is the economy and the cost of living in this country.
我想今晚首先讨论选民们反复提到的头号问题，那就是这个国家的经济和生活成本。
Vice President Harris, you and President Trump were elected four years ago, and your opponent on the stage here tonight often asks his supporters, are you better off than you were four years ago?
哈里斯副总统，您和特朗普总统四年前当选，而您今晚在这里的对手常常问他的支持者，你们比四年前过得更好吗？
When it comes to the economy, do you believe Americans are better off than they were four years ago?
在经济方面，您认为美国人比四年前过得更好吗？
So, I was raised as a middle class kid, and I am actually the only person on this stage who has a plan that is about lifting up the middle class and working people of America.
我是作为一个中产阶级的孩子长大的，实际上我是这个舞台上唯一有计划提升美国中产阶级和工人阶级的候选人。
I believe in the ambition, the aspirations, the dreams of the American people.
我相信美国人民的雄心、愿望和梦想。
And that is why I imagine and have actually a plan to build what I call an opportunity economy.
这就是为什么我设想并实际上有一个计划来建立我所称的机会经济。
Because here's the thing.
因为事情是这样的。
We know that we have a shortage of homes and housing.
我们知道我们面临住房和房屋的短缺。
And the cost of housing is too expensive for far too many people.
而住房成本对于太多人来说实在过于昂贵。
We know that young families need support.
我们知道年轻家庭需要支持。
to raise their children, and I intend on extending a tax cut for those families of $6,000, which is the largest child tax credit that we have given in a long time, so that those young families can afford to buy a crib, buy a car seat, buy clothes for their children.
来抚养他们的孩子，我打算为这些家庭提供6000美元的减税，这是我们很长时间以来给予的最大的儿童税收抵免，这样这些年轻家庭就能负担得起婴儿床、汽车座椅和孩子的衣物。
My passion, one of them, is small businesses.
我的热情之一是小企业。
I was actually – my mother raised my sister and me, but there was a woman who helped raise us.
实际上，我的母亲抚养了我和我的妹妹，但有一位女性帮助我们成长。
We call her our second mother.
我们称她为我们的第二个母亲。
She was a small business owner.
她是一位小企业主。
I love our small businesses.
我爱我们的中小企业。
My plan is to give a $50,000 tax deduction to startup small businesses, knowing they are part of the backbone of America's economy.
我的计划是给初创小企业提供5万美元的税收减免，因为我知道它们是美国经济的支柱。
My opponent, on the other hand, his plan is to do what he has done before.
而我的对手，他的计划是重蹈覆辙。
which is to provide a tax cut for billionaires and big corporations, which will result in $5 trillion to America's deficit.
就是为亿万富翁和大公司提供减税，这将导致美国的赤字增加5万亿美元。
My opponent has a plan that I call the Trump sales tax, which would be a 20% tax on everyday goods that you rely on to get through the month.
我的对手有一个我称之为特朗普销售税的计划，这将对你们每月依赖的日常商品征收20%的税。
Economists have said that that Trump sales tax would actually result for middle-class families in about $4,000 more a year because of his policies and his ideas about what should be the backs of middle-class people paying for tax cuts for billionaires.
经济学家们表示，这项特朗普销售税实际上将使中产阶级家庭每年多花约4000美元，因为他的政策和他对中产阶级应为亿万富翁减税买单的看法。
President Trump.
特朗普总统。
Tariff will be substantial in some cases.
在某些情况下，关税将是相当可观的。
I took in billions and billions of dollars as you know from China In fact, they never took the tariff off because it was so much money They can't it would totally destroy everything that they've set out to do They're taking in billions of dollars from China and other places They've left the tariffs on when I had it I had tariffs and yet I had no inflation look, we've had a
正如你所知道的，我从中国获得了数十亿美元。事实上，他们从未取消关税，因为那是如此巨额的资金，他们无法做到，这将完全摧毁他们所设定的一切。他们从中国和其他地方收入数十亿美元。当我执政时，我实施了关税，但我没有经历通货膨胀。看看，我们的经济
Terrible economy because inflation has which is really known as a country buster.
因为通货膨胀而变得糟糕，这实际上被称为国家破坏者。
It breaks up countries We have inflation like very few people have ever seen before probably the worst in our nation's history We were at 21 percent But that's being generous because many things are 50 60 70 and 80 percent higher than they were just a few years ago This has been a disaster for people for the middle class but for every class on top of that we have millions of people pouring into our country from
它使国家分崩离析。我们经历的通货膨胀是极少数人所见过的，可能是我们国家历史上最糟糕的。我们曾达到21%的通货膨胀，但那是宽容的，因为许多东西比几年前高出50%、60%、70%和80%。这对中产阶级来说是灾难，但对每个阶级来说都是如此。此外，我们还有数百万人从
prisons and jails from mental institutions and insane asylums.
监狱和精神病院涌入我们的国家。
And they're coming in and they're taking jobs that are occupied right now by African Americans and Hispanics and also unions.
他们正在进入并占据现在由非裔美国人和西班牙裔人以及工会占据的工作。
Unions are going to be affected very soon.
工会将很快受到影响。
And you see what's happening.
你看到发生了什么。
You see what's happening with towns throughout the United States.
你看到美国各地城镇发生了什么。
You look at Springfield, Ohio.
你看看俄亥俄州的斯普林菲尔德。
You look at Aurora in Colorado.
你看看科罗拉多州的奥罗拉。
They are taking over the towns.
他们正在占领这些城镇。
They're taking over buildings.
他们正在占领建筑物。
They're going in violently.
他们以暴力的方式进入。
These are the people that she and Biden let into our country, and they're destroying our country.
这些人是她和拜登让进入我们国家的，他们正在摧毁我们的国家。
They're dangerous.
他们很危险。
They're at the highest level of criminality, and we have to get them out.
他们的犯罪率处于最高水平，我们必须把他们赶出去。
We have to get them out fast.
我们必须迅速把他们赶出去。
I created one of the greatest economies in the history of our country.
我创造了我们国家历史上最伟大的经济之一。
I'll do it again and even better.
我会再次做到，甚至做得更好。
We are going to get to immigration and border security during this debate, but I would like to let Vice President Harris respond on the economy here.
在这次辩论中，我们将讨论移民和边境安全，但我想让哈里斯副总统在经济问题上做出回应。
Well, I would love to.
我非常乐意。
Let's talk about what Donald Trump left us.
让我们来谈谈唐纳德·特朗普留给我们的。
Donald Trump left us the worst unemployment since the Great Depression.
特朗普给我们留下了自大萧条以来最糟糕的失业率
Donald Trump left us the worst public health epidemic in a century.
特朗普给我们留下了一个世纪以来最严重的公共卫生疫情
Donald Trump left us the worst attack on our democracy since the Civil War.
特朗普给我们留下了自内战以来对我们民主的最严重攻击
And what we have done is clean up Donald Trump's mess.
而我们所做的就是清理特朗普留下的烂摊子
What we have done and what I intend to do is build on what we know are the aspirations and the hopes of the American people.
我们所做的以及我打算做的，是在我们所知道的美国人民的愿望和希望的基础上继续前进
But I'm going to tell you on this debate tonight, you're going to hear from the same old tired playbook.
但我告诉你，今晚的辩论中，你将听到同样老套的剧本
A bunch of lies, grievances, and name-calling.
一堆谎言、怨言和人身攻击
What you're going to hear tonight is a detailed and dangerous plan called Project 2025 that the former president intends on implementing if he were elected again.
你今晚要听到的是一个详细而危险的计划，名为Project 2025，前总统打算在再次当选时实施
I believe very strongly that the American people want a president who understands the importance of bringing us together, knowing we have so much more in common than what separates us.
我坚信，美国人民希望有一位理解团结重要性的总统，知道我们之间有更多的共同点而非分歧
And I pledge to you to be a president for all Americans.
我向你们承诺，成为所有美国人的总统
President Trump will give you a minute here to respond.
特朗普总统将给你一分钟时间回应
Number one, I have nothing to do, as you know, and as she knows better than anyone, I have nothing to do with Project 2025.
第一，我与Project 2025没有任何关系，正如你所知，正如她比任何人都知道的，我与此毫无关系
That's out there.
这个计划已经被提出了
I haven't read it.
我还没读过它
I don't want to read it purposely.
我故意不想去读它
I'm not going to read it.
我不会去读它
This was a group of people that got together.
这是一个团队聚在一起的结果
They came up with some ideas, I guess some good, some bad, but it makes no difference.
他们提出了一些想法，有些好，有些坏，但这无关紧要
I have nothing to do.
我与此毫无关系
Everybody knows I'm an open book.
大家都知道我是一本公开的书
Everybody knows what I'm going to do.
大家都知道我会做什么
Cut taxes very substantially and create a great economy like I did before.
大幅减税，创造一个像我之前那样的伟大经济
We had the greatest economy.
我们曾经拥有最伟大的经济
We got hit with a pandemic.
我们遭遇了疫情
And the pandemic was not since 1917, where 100 million people died.
而这场疫情自1917年以来，从未发生过，导致1亿人死亡
Has there been anything like it?
有过类似的吗？
We did a phenomenal job with the pandemic.
我们在疫情期间表现得非常出色
We handed them over a country where the economy and where the stock market was higher than it was before the pandemic came in.
我们把一个经济和股市在疫情之前更高的国家交给了他们
Nobody's ever seen anything like it.
没有人见过这样的事情
We made ventilators for the entire world.
我们为整个世界制造了呼吸机
We got gowns.
我们有礼服。
We got masks.
我们有口罩。
We did things that nobody thought possible.
我们做了没人认为可能的事情。
And people give me credit for rebuilding the military.
人们都给我赞誉，称我重建了军队。
They give me credit for a lot of things, but not enough credit for the great job we did with the pandemic.
他们对我赞誉颇多，但对我们在疫情中所做的伟大工作赞誉不够。
But the only jobs they got were bounce-back jobs.
但他们得到的唯一工作是复苏工作。
These were jobs bounce-back, and it bounced back and it went to their benefit.
这些是复苏的工作，复苏了，并且对他们有利。
But I was the one that created them.
但我是创造这些工作的那个人。
They know it, and so does everybody else.
他们知道这一点，其他人也知道。
Vice President Harris, I'll let you respond.
哈里斯副总统，我让您回应。
Donald Trump has no plan for you.
唐纳德·特朗普没有为你们制定计划。
And when you look at his economic plan, it's all about tax breaks for the richest people.
当你看看他的经济计划时，这全是给最富有的人减税。
I am offering what I describe as an opportunity economy, and the best economists in our country, if not the world, have reviewed our relative plans for the future of America.
我提供的是我所描述的机会经济，而我们国家，甚至是世界上最优秀的经济学家们，已经审查了我们未来计划的相关性。
What Goldman Sachs has said is that Donald Trump's plan would make the economy worse, mine would strengthen the economy.
高盛所说的是，唐纳德·特朗普的计划会使经济变得更糟，而我的计划会增强经济。
What the Wharton School has said is Donald Trump's plan would actually explode the deficit.
沃顿商学院所说的是，唐纳德·特朗普的计划实际上会导致赤字激增。
Sixteen Nobel laureates have described his economic plan as something that would increase inflation and by the middle of next year would invite a recession.
十六位诺贝尔奖得主将他的经济计划描述为会增加通货膨胀，并且到明年中期会引发衰退。
You just have to look at where we are and where we stand on the issues.
你只需看看我们现在的位置以及我们在这些问题上的立场。
And I'd invite you to know that Donald Trump actually has no plan for you, because he is more interested in defending himself than he is in looking out for you.
我想邀请你们知道，唐纳德·特朗普实际上没有为你们制定计划，因为他更关心为自己辩护，而不是关心你们。
It's just a soundbite.
这只是一个声响片段。
They gave her that to say, look, I went to the Wharton School of Finance and many of those professors, the top professors think my plan is a brilliant plan.
他们让她这样说，看看，我去了沃顿商学院，许多顶尖教授认为我的计划是个绝妙的计划。
It's a great plan.
这是一个伟大的计划。
It's a plan that's going to bring up our worth, our value as a country.
这是一个将提升我们国家价值的计划。
It's going to make people want to be able to go and work and
这将让人们想去工作，并且
and create jobs and create a lot of good, solid money for our country.
创造就业机会，为我们的国家创造大量良好、稳固的财富。
Just to finish off, she doesn't have a plan.
最后，她没有计划。
She copied Biden's plan, and it's like four sentences, like run, spot, run, four sentences that are just, oh, we'll try and lower taxes.
她抄袭了拜登的计划，就像四句话，像“跑，Spot，跑”，四句话只是，哦，我们会试着降低税收。
She doesn't have a plan.
她没有计划。
Take a look at her plan.
看看她的计划。
She doesn't have a plan.
她没有计划。
Mr. President, I do want to drill down on something you both brought up.
总统先生，我确实想深入探讨你们两人都提到的某些内容。
The Vice President brought up your tariffs.
副总统提到了你的关税。
You responded, and let's drill down on this, because your plan is what she calls is essentially a national sales tax.
你回应了，让我们深入探讨一下，因为你的计划被她称为本质上是一个全国销售税。
Your proposal calls for tariffs, as you pointed out here, on foreign imports across the board.
正如你在这里指出的，你的提案要求对所有外国进口商品征收关税。
You recently said that you might double your plan, imposing tariffs up to 20 percent on goods coming into this country.
你最近表示，你可能会将你的计划翻倍，对进入这个国家的商品征收高达20%的关税。
As you know, many economists say that with tariffs at that level, costs are then passed on to the consumer.
如你所知，许多经济学家认为，关税达到那个水平时，成本将会转嫁给消费者。
Vice President Harris has argued it'll mean higher prices on gas, food, clothing, medication, arguing it costs the typical family nearly $4,000 a year.
哈里斯副总统辩称，这将导致汽油、食品、衣物和药物的价格上涨，认为普通家庭每年将多花近4000美元。
Do you believe Americans can afford higher prices because of tariffs?
你认为美国人能承受因关税而上涨的价格吗？
They're not going to have higher prices.
他们不会有更高的价格。
What's going to happen, who's going to have higher prices is China and all of the countries that have been ripping us off for years.
将会有更高价格的是中国和那些多年来一直在剥削我们的国家。
I charge, I was the only president ever,
我敢说，我是历史上唯一一位。
China is paying us hundreds of billions of dollars and so are other countries.
中国已经支付我们数千亿美元，其他国家也是。
billions of dollars, hundreds of billions of dollars.
数十亿美元，数百亿美元。
I had no inflation, virtually no inflation.
我几乎没有通货膨胀，几乎没有通货膨胀。
They had the highest inflation, perhaps, in the history of our country, because I've never seen a worse period of time.
他们的通货膨胀可能是我们国家历史上最高的，因为我从未见过如此糟糕的时期。
People can't go out and buy cereal or bacon or eggs or anything else.
人们无法外出购买谷物、培根、鸡蛋或其他任何东西。
These the people of our country are absolutely dying with what they've done.
我们国家的人们因他们所做的事情而感到绝望。
They've destroyed the economy.
他们毁了经济。
And all you have to do is look at a poll.
你只需看看民调。
The polls say 80 and 85 and even 90 percent that the Trump economy was great, that their economy was terrible.
民调显示80%、85%甚至90%的人认为特朗普的经济非常好，而他们的经济糟糕。
Vice President Harris, I do want to ask for your response.
哈里斯副总统，我确实想问你对此的回应。
And you heard what the president said there, because the Biden administration did keep a number of the Trump tariffs in place.
你听到了总统在那里的发言，因为拜登政府确实保留了一些特朗普的关税政策。
So how do you respond?
那么你怎么回应呢？
Well, let's be clear that the Trump administration resulted in a trade deficit, one of the highest we've ever seen in the history of America.
好吧，让我们明确一点，特朗普政府导致了贸易赤字，这是我们美国历史上最高的之一。
He invited trade wars.
他挑起了贸易战争。
You want to talk about his deal with China, what he ended up doing is under Donald Trump's presidency, he ended up selling American chips
你想谈谈他与中国的协议，他在特朗普总统任内所做的就是将美国芯片
to China to help them improve and modernize their military basically sold us out when a policy about China should be in making sure the United States of America wins the competition for the 21st century.
卖给中国，以帮助他们改善和现代化他们的军队，基本上是在出卖我们，而针对中国的政策应该是确保美国赢得21世纪的竞争。
which means focusing on the details of what that requires, focusing on relationships with our allies, focusing on investing in American-based technology so that we win the race on AI, on quantum computing, focusing on what we need to do to support America's workforce so that we don't end up having, on the short end of the stick,
这意味着关注实现这一目标所需的细节，关注与我们的盟友的关系，关注投资美国本土技术，以便我们在人工智能和量子计算的竞争中胜出，关注我们需要做什么来支持美国的劳动力，以便我们不会在
in terms of workers' rights.
工人权益方面处于劣势。
But what Donald Trump did—let's talk about this—with COVID is he actually thanked President Xi for what he did during COVID.
但特朗普所做的——让我们谈谈这个——在COVID期间，他实际上感谢习近平主席在COVID期间所做的事情。
Look at his tweet.
看看他的推特。
Thank you, President Xi!
谢谢你，习近平主席！
When we know that Xi was responsible for lacking and not giving us transparency about the origins of COVID.
当我们知道习近平对COVID起源缺乏透明度时。
President Trump, I'll let you respond.
特朗普总统，我让你回应。
First of all, they bought their chips from Taiwan.
首先，他们从台湾购买芯片。
We hardly make chips anymore because of philosophies like they have and policies like they have.
由于他们的理念和政策，我们几乎不再制造芯片了。
I don't say her because she has no policy.
我不说她，因为她没有政策。
Everything that she believed three years ago and four years ago is out the window.
她三年前和四年前所相信的一切都已不复存在。
She's going to my philosophy now.
她现在采纳了我的理念。
In fact, I was going to send her a MAGA hat.
事实上，我本来打算给她寄一顶“让美国再次伟大”的帽子。
She's gone to my philosophy.
她已经转向了我的理念。
If she ever got elected, she'd change it, and it will be the end of our country.
如果她当选，她会改变这一切，那将是我们国家的终结。
She's a Marxist.
她是一个马克思主义者。
Everybody knows she's a Marxist.
大家都知道她是一个马克思主义者。
Her father's a Marxist professor in economics, and he taught her well.
她的父亲是一位经济学的马克思主义教授，他教得很好。
But when you look at what she's done to our country, and when you look at these millions and millions of people that are pouring into our country monthly, where it's, I believe, 21 million people, not the 15 that people say,
但是当你看看她对我们国家所做的事情，以及每月涌入我们国家的数以百万计的人时，我相信有2100万人，而不是人们所说的1500万，
And I think it's a lot higher than the 21.
我认为这个数字远高于2100万。
That's bigger than New York State pouring in.
这比纽约州的人口还要多。
And just look at what they're doing to our country.
看看他们对我们国家所造成的影响。
They're criminals.
他们是罪犯。
Many of these people coming in are criminals.
这些涌入的人中有很多是罪犯。
And that's bad for our economy, too.
这对我们的经济也很糟糕。
You know, you mentioned before, we'll talk about immigration later.
你知道，你之前提到过，我们稍后会讨论移民问题。
Well, bad immigration is the worst thing that can happen to our economy.
糟糕的移民是对我们经济最糟糕的事情。
They have, and she has, destroyed our country with policy that's insane.
他们已经，她也已经，用疯狂的政策摧毁了我们的国家。
Almost policy that you'd say they have to hate our country.
几乎是那种你会说他们必须仇恨我们国家的政策。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢你。
Lindsey?
林赛？
I want to turn to the issue of abortion.
我想转向堕胎问题。
President Trump, you've often touted that you were able to kill Roe v. Wade last year.
特朗普总统，你常常宣称你去年成功推翻了《罗诉韦德案》。
You said that you were proud to be the most pro-life president in American history.
你说你为自己成为美国历史上最支持生命的总统而感到自豪。
Then last month, you said that your administration would be great for women and their reproductive rights.
然后上个月，你说你的政府将对女性及其生育权大有裨益。
In your home state of Florida, you surprised many with regard to your six-week abortion ban, because you initially had said that it was too short.
在你的家乡佛罗里达州，你在六周堕胎禁令问题上让许多人感到惊讶，因为你最初曾表示这期限过短。
And you said, quote, I'm going to be voting that we need more than six weeks.
你还说过，引用，“我将投票支持需要超过六周的规定。”
But then, the very next day, you reversed course and said you would vote to support the six-week ban.
但是，紧接着的第二天，你又改变了立场，表示你会投票支持六周的禁令。
Vice President Harris says that women shouldn't trust you on the issue of abortion because you've changed your position so many times.
哈里斯副总统表示，女性在堕胎问题上不应信任你，因为你已经多次改变立场。
Therefore, why should they trust you?
那么，为什么她们应该信任你呢？
The reason I'm doing that vote is because the plan is, as you know, the voters, they have abortion in the ninth month.
我之所以投票是因为，正如你所知道的，选民们认为在第九个月也可以堕胎。
They even have and you can look at the governor of West Virginia, the previous governor of West Virginia, not the current governor is doing an excellent job, but the governor before he said
你甚至可以看看西弗吉尼亚州的前州长，不是现在的州长做得很好，而是前任州长曾说过：
The baby will be born, and we will decide what to do with the baby.
“婴儿将出生，我们将决定如何处理这个婴儿。”
In other words, we'll execute the baby.
换句话说，我们会处决这个婴儿。
And that's why I did that, because that predominates.
这就是我这样做的原因，因为这是占主导地位的观点。
Because they're radical.
因为他们是激进的。
The Democrats are radical in that.
民主党人在这一点上是激进的。
And her vice presidential pick, which I think is a horrible pick, by the way, for our country, because he is really out of it.
而她的副总统人选，我认为这是对我们国家的一个糟糕选择，因为他真的不在状态。
But her vice presidential pick says abortion in the ninth month is absolutely fine.
但她的副总统人选表示，第九个月的堕胎是绝对可以的。
He also says execution after birth, it's execution, no longer abortion because the baby is born, is okay.
他还说，出生后的处决，不再是堕胎，因为婴儿已经出生，是可以的。
And that's not okay with me, hence the vote.
这对我来说是不可接受的，因此我投了这个票。
But what I did is something for
但我所做的是，
52 years they've been trying to get Roe v. Wade into the states.
他们已经努力了52年想要将《罗诉韦德案》带回各州。
And through the genius and heart and strength of six Supreme Court justices, we were able to do that.
凭借六位最高法院法官的智慧、勇气和力量，我们终于能够做到这一点。
Now, I believe in the exceptions for
现在，我相信在
rape, incest, and life of the mother.
强奸、乱伦和母亲生命的例外情况下。
I believe strongly in it.
我对此深信不疑。
Ronald Reagan did also.
罗纳德·里根也是如此。
Eighty-five percent of Republicans do.
85%的共和党人也这样认为。
Exceptions.
例外情况。
Very important.
非常重要。
But we were able to get it, and now states are voting on it.
但我们已经做到，现在各州正在对此进行投票。
And for the first time, you're going to see — look, this is an issue that's torn our country apart for 52 years.
这是第一次，你将看到——听着，这是一个在过去52年中撕裂我们国家的问题。
Every legal scholar, every Democrat, every Republican, liberal, conservative, they all wanted this issue to be brought back to the states where the people could vote.
每位法律学者、每位民主党人、每位共和党人、自由派、保守派，他们都希望将这个问题带回各州，让人民投票。
And that's what happened.
这就是发生的事情。
Now, Ohio, the vote was somewhat liberal.
现在，俄亥俄州的投票相对偏向自由派。
Kansas, the vote was somewhat liberal, much more liberal than people would have thought.
堪萨斯州的投票也相对偏向自由派，远比人们想象的要 liberal。
But each individual state
但是每个州
is voting.
都在投票。
It's the vote of the people now.
现在是人民的投票。
It's not tied up in the federal government.
这与联邦政府无关。
I did a great service in doing it.
我这样做是为了服务大众。
It took courage to do it.
这需要勇气。
And the Supreme Court had great courage in doing it.
最高法院在这方面表现出极大的勇气。
And I give tremendous credit to those six justices.
我对那六位法官给予了极大的赞誉。
There is no state in this country where it is legal to kill a baby after it's born.
在这个国家，没有哪个州允许在婴儿出生后杀死婴儿。
Madam Vice President, I want to get your response to President Trump.
哈里斯副总统，我想听听您对特朗普总统的回应。
Well, as I said, you're going to hear a bunch of lies, and that's not actually a surprising fact.
好吧，正如我所说，你将听到一堆谎言，这并不是一个令人惊讶的事实。
Let's understand how we got here.
让我们理解一下我们是如何走到这一步的。
Donald Trump hand-selected three members of the United States Supreme Court with the intention that they would undo the protections of Roe v. Wade.
唐纳德·特朗普手选了三位美国最高法院法官，目的是为了推翻罗诉韦德案的保护。
And they did exactly as he intended.
而他们正如他所意图的那样做了。
And now in over 20 states, there are Trump abortion bans, which make it criminal for a doctor or nurse to provide health care.
现在在超过20个州，实施了特朗普的堕胎禁令，这使得医生或护士提供医疗服务成为犯罪。
In one state, it provides prison for life.
在一个州，这将导致终身监禁。
Trump abortion bans that make no exception even for rape and incest, which understand what that means.
特朗普的堕胎禁令甚至没有针对强奸和乱伦的例外，大家要理解这意味着什么。
A survivor of a crime, a violation to their body, does not have the right to make a decision about what happens to their body next.
一个犯罪的幸存者，身体遭受侵犯，却没有权利决定接下来发生在她身体上的事情。
That is immoral.
这是不道德的。
And one does not have to abandon their faith or deeply held beliefs to agree.
而且一个人不必放弃自己的信仰或深信不疑的信念来同意这一点。
The government, and Donald Trump certainly, should not be telling a woman what to do with her body.
政府，当然包括唐纳德·特朗普，绝不应该告诉女性该如何处理自己的身体。
I have talked with women around our country.
我与全国各地的女性交谈过。
You want to talk about this is what people wanted?
你想谈谈这就是人们所想要的吗？
Pregnant women who want to carry a pregnancy to term, suffering from a miscarriage, being denied care in an emergency room because the health care providers are afraid they might go to jail, and she's bleeding out in a car in the parking lot.
怀孕的女性想要把孕期坚持到底，遭遇流产，却因为医疗提供者害怕入狱而在急救室被拒绝治疗，她在停车场的车里出血。
She didn't want that.
她并不想这样。
Her husband didn't want that.
她的丈夫也不想这样。
A 12 or 13-year-old survivor of incest being forced to carry a pregnancy to term.
一个12或13岁的乱伦幸存者被迫把怀孕坚持到分娩。
They don't want that.
他们不想要那个
And I pledge to you, when Congress passes a bill to put back in place the protections of Roe v. Wade as President of the United States, I will proudly sign it into law.
我向你们承诺，当国会通过一项法案，恢复《罗伊诉韦德案》的保护时，作为美国总统，我将自豪地签署该法案成为法律
But understand, if Donald Trump were to be reelected, he will sign a national abortion ban.
但要明白，如果唐纳德·特朗普重新当选，他将签署一项全国性堕胎禁令
Understand, in his Project 2025, there would be a national abortion monitor that would be monitoring your pregnancies, your miscarriages.
要知道，在他的《项目2025》中，将会有一个全国性堕胎监测机构，监控你的怀孕和流产情况
I think the American people believe
我认为美国人民相信
that certain freedoms, in particular the freedom to make decisions about one's own body, should not be made by the government.
某些自由，特别是关于自己身体的决策自由，不应由政府来决定
Thank you, Vice President Harris.
谢谢你，哈里斯副总统
Well, there she goes again.
好吧，她又来了
It's a lie.
这是谎言
I'm not signing a ban and there's no reason to sign a ban because
我不会签署禁令，也没有理由去签署禁令，因为
We've gotten what everybody wanted.
我们得到了大家想要的
Democrats, Republicans, and everybody else, and every legal scholar wanted it to be brought back into the states.
民主党人、共和党人以及其他所有人，还有每位法律学者，都希望将这个问题交还给各州
And the states are voting.
各州正在投票
And it may take a little time.
这可能需要一点时间
But for 52 years, this issue has torn our country apart.
但在过去52年里，这个问题一直撕裂着我们的国家
And they've wanted it back in the states.
他们希望将其交还给各州
And I did something that nobody thought was possible.
我做了一件没有人认为可能的事情
The states are now voting.
各州现在正在投票
What she says is an absolute lie.
她所说的完全是谎言
And as far as the abortion ban, no, I'm not in favor of abortion ban, but it doesn't matter because this issue has now been taken over by the states.
至于堕胎禁令，不，我不支持堕胎禁令，但这无所谓，因为这个问题现在已经由各州接管
Would you veto a national abortion ban if it came to your desk?
如果一项全国性堕胎禁令送到你桌面上，你会否决它吗
Well, I won't have to because, again, two things.
我根本不需要，因为，再说两件事
Number one, she said she'll go back to Congress.
第一，她说她会回到国会
She'll never get the vote.
她永远不会得到投票
It's impossible for her to get the vote, especially now with the 50-50, essentially 50-50 in both Senate and the House.
她不可能获得投票，特别是在参议院和众议院基本上是50-50的情况下
She's not going to get the vote.
她不会得到投票
She can't get the vote.
她无法获得投票
She won't even come close to it.
她甚至不会接近
So it's just talk.
所以这只是空谈
You know what it reminds me of?
你知道这让我想起什么吗
When they said they're going to get student loans terminated, and it ended up being a total catastrophe.
当他们说要取消学生贷款时，结果完全是一场灾难。
This is
这就是
taunted with this whole thing about this whole idea and how unfair that would have been part of the reason they lost to The millions and millions of people that had to pay off their student loans.
与这个想法相关的嘲讽，以及这可能是他们输给那些必须偿还学生贷款的数百万人的部分原因。
They didn't get it for free But they were saying it's the same way that they talked about that that they talk about abortion.
他们并没有免费获得这些贷款，但他们谈论这些问题的方式就像谈论堕胎一样。
But if I could just get a yes or no, because you're running me, J.D.
但如果我能得到一个是或否，因为你在逼我，J.D.
Vance has said that you would veto if it did come to your desk.
范斯说如果这真的到了你的桌子上，你会否决它。
Well, I didn't discuss it with J.D.
好吧，我没有和J.D.讨论这个。
In all fairness, J.D., and I don't mind if he has a certain view, but I think he was speaking for me, but I really didn't.
公平地说，J.D.，我不介意他有某种观点，但我认为他是在为我发言，但我其实并没有。
We don't have to discuss it, because she'd never be able to get it.
我们不必讨论这个，因为她永远不可能得到它。
Just like she couldn't get student loans, they couldn't get student loans.
就像她无法获得学生贷款一样，他们也无法获得学生贷款。
They didn't even come close to getting student loans.
他们甚至连获得学生贷款的机会都没有。
They taunted young people and a lot of other people that had loans.
他们嘲讽年轻人和许多其他有贷款的人。
They can never get this approved.
他们永远无法获得批准。
So it doesn't matter what she says about going to Congress.
所以她说的关于去国会的事毫无意义。
Oh, wonderful.
哦，太好了。
Let's go to Congress.
让我们去国会。
Do it.
去做吧。
But the fact is that for years, they wanted to get it out of Congress and out of the federal government.
但事实是多年来，他们想要将其从国会和联邦政府中移除。
And we did something that everybody said couldn't be done.
而我们做了所有人都说无法做到的事情。
And now you have a vote of the people on abortion.
现在你们在堕胎问题上有了公众投票。
Vice President Harris, I want to give you your time to respond, but I do want to ask, would you support any restrictions on a woman's right to an abortion?
哈里斯副总统，我想给你时间回应，但我确实想问，你会支持对女性堕胎权的任何限制吗？
I absolutely support reinstating the protections of Roe v. Wade, and as you rightly mentioned, nowhere in America
我绝对支持恢复罗诉韦德案的保护，正如你所提到的，在美国的任何地方
is a woman carrying a pregnancy to term and asking for an abortion.
没有女性在怀孕期间要求堕胎。
That is not happening.
这根本没有发生。
It's insulting to the women of America.
这对美国女性来说是种侮辱。
And understand what has been happening under Donald Trump's abortion bans.
并且要理解在特朗普的堕胎禁令下发生了什么。
Couples who pray and dream of having a family are being denied IVF treatments.
渴望拥有家庭的夫妇被拒绝了试管婴儿治疗。
What is happening in our country?
我们国家发生了什么？
Working people, working women who are working one or two jobs, who can barely afford child care as it is, have to travel to another state to get on a plane sitting next to strangers to go and get the health care she needs.
那些做一两份工作的女性，几乎无法负担托儿费用，必须去另一个州，坐在陌生人旁边的飞机上，去获得她所需的医疗保健。
barely can afford to do it, and what you are putting her through is unconscionable.
她几乎负担不起这样做，而你让她经历的事情是无法容忍的。
And the people of America have not—the majority of Americans believe in a woman's right to make decisions about her own body, and that is why, in every state where this issue has been on the ballot, in red and blue states both, the people of America have voted for freedom.
美国人民并没有——大多数美国人相信女性有权对自己的身体做出决定，这就是为什么在每个州，这个问题出现在投票中，无论是红州还是蓝州，美国人民都投票支持自由。
vice president
副总统
I saw the people of Alabama and the legislature two days later voted it in.
我看到阿拉巴马州的人们和立法机关在两天后投票通过了。
I've been a leader on it.
我在这方面一直是个领导者。
They know that and everybody else knows it.
他们知道这一点，其他人也知道。
I have been a leader on fertilization IVF.
我一直是试管婴儿受精方面的领导者。
And the other thing, they, you should ask, will she allow abortion in the eighth month, ninth month, seventh month?
另外一件事，你应该问，她会允许在第八个月、第九个月、第七个月进行堕胎吗？
Come on.
来吧。
Okay, would you do that?
好吧，你会这么做吗？
Why don't you ask her that question?
为什么不问她这个问题？
That's the problem.
这就是问题所在。
Because under Roe v. Wade, you could do abortions in the seventh month, the eighth month, the ninth month, and probably after birth.
因为根据《罗诉韦德案》，你可以在第七个月、第八个月、第九个月，甚至可能在出生后进行堕胎。
Just look at the governor, former governor of Virginia.
看看维吉尼亚州的州长，前州长。
The governor of Virginia said we put the baby aside and then we determine what we want to do with the baby.
维吉尼亚州的州长说我们把婴儿放在一边，然后我们决定要对婴儿做什么。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢。
We're going to turn now to immigration and border security.
现在我们将转向移民和边境安全。
We know it's an issue that's important to Republicans, Democrats, voters across the board in this country.
我们知道这是对共和党人、民主党人和全国选民都非常重要的问题。
Vice President Harris, you were tasked by President Biden with getting to the root causes of migration from Central America.
哈里斯副总统，拜登总统让您负责解决中美洲移民的根本原因。
We know that illegal border crossings reached a record high in the Biden administration.
我们知道在拜登政府期间，非法越境达到了创纪录的高点。
This past June, President Biden imposed tough new asylum restrictions.
在今年六月，拜登总统实施了严格的新庇护限制。
We know the numbers since then have dropped significantly.
我们知道自那以来，数字显著下降。
But my question to you tonight is, why did the administration wait until six months before the election to act?
但我今晚要问你的问题是，为什么政府在选举前六个月才采取行动？
And would you have done anything differently from President Biden on this?
如果是你，你会和拜登总统有什么不同的做法吗？
So I'm the only person on this stage who has prosecuted transnational criminal organizations for the trafficking of guns, drugs and human beings.
所以我是这个舞台上唯一一个起诉跨国犯罪组织，打击枪支、毒品和人口贩卖的人。
And let me say that the United States Congress, including some of the most conservative members of the United States Senate, came up with a border security bill, which I supported.
让我说，美国国会，包括一些最保守的参议员，提出了一项边境安全法案，我支持这项法案。
And that bill would have put 1,500 more border agents on the border to help those folks who are working there right now, over time, trying to do their job.
这项法案将增加1500名边境执法人员，以帮助那些正在努力工作的执法人员。
It would have allowed us to stem the flow of fentanyl coming into the United States.
这将使我们能够遏制芬太尼流入美国的情况。
I know there are so many families watching tonight who have been personally affected
我知道今晚有很多家庭在观看，他们个人受到芬太尼激增的影响。
by the surge of fentanyl in our country.
这项法案将提供更多资源，让我们能够起诉跨国犯罪组织，打击枪支、毒品和人口贩卖。
That bill would have put more resources to allow us to prosecute transnational criminal organizations for trafficking in guns, drugs, and human beings.
这将为我们打击跨国犯罪提供必要的支持。
But you know what happened to that bill?
但你知道那项法案发生了什么吗？
Donald Trump got on the phone, called up some folks in Congress, and said, kill the bill.
唐纳德·特朗普打电话给国会的一些人，让他们杀掉这项法案。
And you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Because he'd prefer to run on a problem instead of fixing a problem.
因为他宁愿在问题上竞选，而不是去解决问题。
And understand, this comes at a time where the people of our country actually need a leader who engages in solutions, who actually addresses the problems at hand.
而且要明白，这发生在我们国家的人们实际上需要一个参与解决方案的领导者，真正去处理当前的问题。
But what we have in the former president is someone who would prefer to run on a problem instead of fixing a problem.
但我们在前总统身上看到的是一个宁愿在问题上竞选而不是解决问题的人。
And I'll tell you something, he's going to talk about immigration a lot tonight, even when it's not the subject that is being raised.
我告诉你，他今晚会谈论移民很多，即使这并不是被提起的话题。
And I'm going to actually do something really unusual, and I'm going to invite you to attend one of Donald Trump's rallies, because it's a really interesting thing to watch.
我将做一件非常不寻常的事，我邀请你参加唐纳德·特朗普的集会，因为这真的是一个非常有趣的事情。
You will see during the course of his rallies, he talks about fictional characters like Hannibal Lecter.
你会看到在他的集会期间，他谈论虚构的人物，比如汉尼拔·莱克特。
He will talk about when mills cause cancer.
他会谈论磨坊如何导致癌症。
And what you will also notice is that people start leaving his rallies early, out of exhaustion and boredom.
你还会注意到，人们开始因为疲惫和无聊而早早离开他的集会。
And I will tell you, the one thing you will not hear him talk about is you.
我告诉你，你不会听到他谈论的是你。
You will not hear him talk about your needs, your dreams, and your desires.
你不会听到他谈论你的需求、你的梦想和你的愿望。
And I'll tell you, I believe you deserve a president who actually puts you first, and I pledge to you that I will.
我告诉你，我相信你值得拥有一个真正把你放在第一位的总统，我向你承诺我会做到。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢你。
President Trump, on that point, I want to get your response.
特朗普总统，对于这一点，我想听听你的回应。
Well, I would like to respond.
好吧，我想回应一下。
Let me just ask, though, why did you try to kill that bill, and successfully so, that would have put thousands of additional agents and officers on the border?
不过让我问一下，为什么你试图杀掉那项法案，并且成功了，那项法案本来会在边境增加数千名额外的特工和警官？
First let me respond is to the rallies.
首先让我回应的是关于集会的事。
She said people start leaving.
她说人们开始离开。
People don't go to her rallies.
人们不去她的集会。
There's no reason to go.
没有理由去。
And the people that do go, she's bussing them in and paying them to be there, and then showing them in a different light.
而且那些去的人，她是用公交车把他们送来的，还给他们支付费用，然后以不同的方式展示他们。
So she can't talk about that.
所以她不能谈论这个。
People don't leave my rallies.
人们不会离开我的集会。
We have the biggest rallies, the most incredible rallies in the history of politics.
我们有历史上最大的集会，最不可思议的集会。
That's because people want to take their country back.
那是因为人们想要夺回他们的国家。
Our country is being lost.
我们的国家正在失去。
We're a failing nation.
我们是一个失败的国家。
And it happened three and a half years ago.
这一切发生在三年半前。
And what's going on here, you're going to end up in World War III, just to go into another subject.
这里发生了什么，你最终会陷入第三次世界大战，只是为了谈论另一个话题。
what they have done to our country by allowing these millions and millions of people to come into our country and look at what's happening to the towns all over the United States.
他们通过允许数以百万计的人进入我们的国家，对我们的国家造成了什么影响，看看美国各地城镇发生了什么。
And a lot of towns don't want to talk.
很多城镇不愿意谈论这个。
It's not going to be Aurora or Springfield.
不会是奥罗拉或斯普林菲尔德。
A lot of towns don't want to talk about it because they're so embarrassed by it.
很多城镇不想谈论这件事，因为他们对此感到非常尴尬。
In Springfield, they're eating the dogs, the people that came in.
在斯普林菲尔德，来的人在吃狗。
They're eating the cats.
他们在吃猫。
They're eating
他们在吃
They're eating the pets of the people that live there.
他们在吃那些住在那里的人的宠物。
And this is what's happening in our country.
这就是我们国家正在发生的事情。
And it's a shame.
这真是太可惜了。
As far as rallies are concerned, as far as — the reason they go is they like what I say.
至于集会，至于——他们去的原因是他们喜欢我说的话。
They want to bring our country back.
他们想让我们的国家恢复往日的辉煌。
They want to make America great again.
他们想让美国再次伟大。
It's a very simple phrase — make America great again.
这是一个非常简单的短语——让美国再次伟大。
She's destroying this country, and if she becomes president, this country doesn't have a chance of success.
她正在摧毁这个国家，如果她成为总统，这个国家就没有成功的机会。
Not only success, we'll end up being Venezuela on steroids.
不仅仅是成功，我们将最终沦落为一个类委内瑞拉的国家。
I just want to clarify here.
我想在这里澄清一下。
You bring up Springfield, Ohio, and ABC News did reach out to the city manager there.
你提到斯普林菲尔德，俄亥俄州，ABC新闻确实联系了那里的市经理。
He told us there had been no credible reports of specific claims of pets being harmed, injured, or abused by individuals within the immigrant community.
他告诉我们，没有关于移民社区内的个体对宠物造成伤害、受伤或虐待的可信报告。
Well, I've seen people on television.
我在电视上见过人们。
The people on television say my dog was taken and used for food.
电视上的人说我的狗被拿走了，成为了食物。
So maybe he said that, and maybe that's a good thing to say for a city manager.
所以，也许他说了这个，也许这对市经理来说是个好说法。
I'm not taking this from television.
我不是从电视上得知这些。
But the people on television say my dog was eaten by the people that went there.
但是电视上的人说我的狗被那些去那的人吃了。
Again, the Springfield city manager says there's no evidence of that.
再次强调，斯普林菲尔德的市经理说没有证据支持这一点。
Vice President Harris, I'll let you respond to the rest of what you've heard.
哈里斯副总统，我让你回应你所听到的其余部分。
You talk about extreme.
你谈到极端。
This is, I think, one of the reasons why, in this election, I actually have the endorsement of 200 Republicans who have formally worked with President Bush, Mitt Romney, and John McCain, including the endorsement of former Vice President Dick Cheney and Congress member Liz Cheney.
我认为，这就是为什么在这次选举中，我实际上得到了200名与布什总统、米特·罗姆尼和约翰·麦凯恩正式合作的共和党的支持，包括前副总统迪克·切尼和国会议员莉兹·切尼的支持。
And if you want to really know the inside track on who the former president is, if he didn't make it clear already, just ask people who have worked with him.
如果你想真正了解前总统是谁，如果他还没有说清楚，只需询问那些与他合作过的人。
His former chief of staff, a four-star general, has said he has contempt for the Constitution of the United States.
他以前的幕僚长，一个四星将军，曾表示他对美国宪法充满蔑视。
His former national security advisor has said he is dangerous and unfit.
他以前的国家安全顾问曾说他是危险的，不适合担任此职。
His former Secretary of Defense has said the nation, the republic, would never survive another Trump term.
他以前的国防部长曾表示，国家和共和国永远无法承受另一个特朗普任期。
And when we listen to this kind of rhetoric, when the issues that affect the American people are not being addressed, I think the choice is clear in this election.
当我们听到这种言辞时，影响美国人民的议题却没有得到解决，我认为在这次选举中选择是明确的。
President Trump will give you a quick minute to respond.
特朗普总统会给你一分钟的时间来回应。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Because when I hear that, see, I'm a different kind of a person.
因为当我听到这些时，你看，我是一个不同类型的人。
I fired most of those people.
我解雇了大多数这些人。
Not so graciously.
不是那么优雅。
They did bad things or a bad job.
他们做了坏事或工作不佳。
I fired them.
我解雇了他们。
They never fired one person.
他们从未解雇过一个人。
They didn't fire anybody having to do with Afghanistan and the Taliban and the 13 people who's who's
他们没有解雇任何与阿富汗和塔利班有关的人，以及那13个
were just killed, viciously and violently killed.
被残忍和暴力杀害的人。
And I got to know the parents and the family.
我认识那些父母和家人。
They didn't fire.
他们没有解雇。
They should have fired all those generals, all those top people, because that was one of the most incompetently handled situations anybody has ever seen.
他们应该解雇所有那些将军，所有那些高层，因为那是任何人见过的处理最无能的情况之一。
So when somebody does a bad job, I fire him.
所以当有人工作不佳时，我就解雇他。
And you take a guy like Esper.
你看看像艾斯珀那种人。
He was no good.
他没用。
I fired him.
我解雇了他。
So he writes a book.
所以他写了一本书。
Another one writes a book.
另一个人写了一本书。
Because with me, they can write books.
因为在我这里，他们可以写书。
With nobody else can they.
在其他人那里，他们不能。
But they have done such a poor job, and they never fire anybody.
但他们做得如此糟糕，他们从未解雇过任何人。
Look at the economy.
看看经济。
Look at the inflation.
看看通货膨胀。
They didn't fire any of their economists.
他们没有解雇任何经济学家。
They have the same people.
他们还是那些人。
That's a good way not to have books written about you.
这是一种让人们不写关于你的书的好方法。
But just to finish, I got more votes than any Republican in history by far.
但我想补充一下，我获得的选票比历史上任何共和党人都要多得多。
In fact, I got more votes than any president, sitting president, in history by far.
事实上，我获得的选票比历史上任何在任总统都要多得多。
Let me continue on immigration.
让我继续谈谈移民问题。
It was what you wanted to talk about earlier.
这正是你之前想讨论的内容。
So let's get back to your deportation proposal that the vice president has reacted to as well.
所以让我们回到副总统对你驱逐提案的反应。
President Trump, you call this the largest domestic deportation operation in the history of our country.
特朗普总统，你称这为我们国家历史上最大的国内驱逐行动。
You say you would use the National Guard.
你说你会动用国民警卫队。
You say if things get out of control, you'd have no problem using the U.S.
你说如果情况失控，你不会有任何问题使用美国
military.
军队。
You also said you would use local police.
你还说你会使用地方警察。
How would you deport 11 million undocumented immigrants?
你打算如何驱逐1100万无证移民？
I know you believe that number is much higher.
我知道你认为这个数字要高得多。
Take us through this.
请给我们详细说明一下。
What does this look like?
这会是什么样子？
Will authorities be going door to door in this country?
当局会在这个国家逐家逐户地去吗？
Yeah, it is much higher because of them.
是的，因为这个数字要高得多，是因为他们的原因。
They allowed criminals, many, many millions of criminals.
他们允许了罪犯，许许多多的罪犯。
They allowed terrorists.
他们允许了恐怖分子。
They allowed common street criminals.
他们允许了普通街头罪犯。
They allowed people to come in, drug dealers to come into our country.
他们允许毒贩进入我们的国家。
And then now in the United States and told by their countries like Venezuela,
然后现在在美国，被他们的国家像委内瑞拉告知，
Don't ever come back or we're going to kill you.
不要再回来，否则我们会杀了你。
Do you know that crime in Venezuela and crime in countries all over the world is way down?
你知道吗，委内瑞拉和世界各地的犯罪率都大幅下降？
You know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Because they've taken their criminals off the street and they've given them to her to put into our country.
因为他们把罪犯从街上清除了，并将他们送给她放进我们的国家。
And this will be one of the greatest mistakes in history for them to allow, and I think they probably did it because they think they're going to get votes, but it's not worth it.
这将是历史上最大的错误之一，他们允许这样做，我认为他们可能是因为认为能得到选票，但这不值得。
because they're destroying the fabric of our country by what they've done.
因为他们正在通过他们所做的事情破坏我们国家的基础。
There's never been anything done like this at all.
从未有过任何事情像这样发生。
They've destroyed the fabric of our country.
他们破坏了我们国家的基础。
Millions of people let in.
数以百万计的人被允许进入。
And all over the world, crime is down all over the world except here.
而在全世界，除了这里，犯罪率都在下降。
Crime here is up and through the roof.
这里的犯罪率却高得离谱。
Despite their fraudulent statements that they made, crime in this country is through the roof.
尽管他们发表了虚假的声明，这个国家的犯罪率仍然高得离谱。
And we have a new form of crime.
而且我们出现了一种新的犯罪形式。
It's called migrant crime.
它被称为移民犯罪。
And it's happening at levels that nobody thought possible.
这种情况的发生率是无人想象的。
President Trump, as you know, the FBI says overall violent crime is actually coming down in this country, but Vice President Harris... Excuse me, the FBI defraud... They were defrauding statements.
特朗普总统，正如您所知，FBI表示这个国家的总体暴力犯罪实际上在下降，但哈里斯副总统……抱歉，FBI的声明是虚假的。
They didn't include the worst cities.
他们没有包括最严重的城市。
They didn't include the cities with the worst crime.
他们没有包括犯罪最严重的城市。
It was a fraud, just like their number of 818,000 jobs that they said they created turned out to be a fraud.
这是一场欺诈，就像他们所说的818,000个工作岗位的数字，结果也被证明是虚假的。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢您。
I'll let you respond, Vice President Harris.
我让您回应，哈里斯副总统。
Well, I think this is so rich, coming from someone who has been prosecuted.
好吧，我认为这真是太可笑了，来自一个被起诉的人。
for national security crimes, economic crimes, election interference, has been found liable for sexual assault, and his next big court appearance is in November at his own criminal sentencing.
因国家安全罪、经济罪、选举干预被起诉，被判定对性侵犯负责，接下来他的大庭审将在11月进行。
And let's be clear where each person stands on the issue of what is important about respect for the rule of law and respect for law enforcement.
让我们明确每个人在法治和执法尊重问题上的立场。
The former vice president called for defunding federal law enforcement, 45,000 agents, get this, on the day after he was arraigned on 34 felony counts.
前副总统在他被控34项重罪的第二天呼吁削减联邦执法机构的资金，涉及45,000名特工。
So let's talk about what is important in this race.
所以让我们谈谈在这场竞选中重要的事情。
It is important that we move forward, that we turn the page on this same old tired rhetoric and address the needs of the American people, address what we need to do about the housing shortage, which I have a plan for, address what we must do to support our small businesses, address bringing down the price of groceries.
重要的是我们要向前迈进，翻开这一套陈腐的说辞，解决美国人民的需求，解决我们需要如何应对住房短缺的问题，我有一个计划，解决我们必须采取的措施来支持小企业，解决降低食品价格的问题。
But, frankly, the American people are exhausted with the same old tired playbook.
但坦率地说，美国人民对这一套陈腐的剧本感到疲惫。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢您。
Excuse me.
抱歉。
Every one of those cases was started by them against their political opponent.
每一个案件都是他们对政治对手提起的。
And I'm winning most of them, and I will win the rest on appeal.
而且我赢得了大多数案件，我会在上诉中赢得其余案件。
And you saw that with the decision that came down just recently from the Supreme Court.
您也看到最近最高法院作出的裁决。
I'm winning most of them.
我赢得了大多数案件。
But those are cases, it's called weaponization, never happened in this country.
但这些案件被称为武器化，在这个国家从未发生过。
They weaponized the Justice Department.
他们武器化了司法部。
Every one of those cases was involved with the DOJ, from Atlanta and Fawny Willis to the Attorney General of New York and the DA in New York.
每一个案件都与司法部有关，从亚特兰大和福尼·威利斯到纽约的检察总长和地方检察官。
Every one of those cases.
每一个案件。
And then they say, oh, he's a criminal.
然后他们说，哦，他是个罪犯。
They're the ones that made them go after me.
是他们让人们去追究我。
By the way, Joe Biden was found essentially guilty on the documents case.
顺便提一下，乔·拜登在文件案件中基本上被认定有罪。
Now, what happened in my documents case?
那么，我的文件案件发生了什么？
They said, oh, that's the toughest of them all.
他们说，哦，那是所有案件中最棘手的。
a complete and total victory.
完全且彻底的胜利。
Two months ago, it was thrown out.
两个月前，它被驳回了。
It's weaponization, and they used it, and it's never happened in this country.
这是武器化，他们利用了这一点，这在这个国家从未发生过。
They used it to try and win an election.
他们用这个来试图赢得选举。
They're fake cases.
这些都是虚假的案件。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢。
A really quick response here, Vice President Harris, on this notion of weaponization of the Justice Department.
副总统哈里斯，您能对司法部武器化的说法做一个简短的回应吗？
Well, let's talk about extreme and understand the context in which this election in 2024 is taking place.
好的，让我们谈谈极端情况，并理解2024年选举的背景。
The United States Supreme Court recently ruled that the former president would essentially be immune from any misconduct if he were to enter the White House again.
美国最高法院最近裁定，前总统如果再次进入白宫，将基本上免于任何不当行为。
Understand this is someone who has openly said he would terminate, I'm quoting, terminate the Constitution of the United States.
请理解，这个人公开表示他会终止——我引用，终止美国宪法。
That he would weaponize the Department of Justice against his political enemies.
他会将司法部武器化，对付他的政治敌人。
Someone who has openly expressed disdain
一个公开表达对我们军队成员蔑视的人。
for members of our military.
请理解，如果唐纳德·特朗普在没有任何约束的情况下回到白宫，这意味着什么。
Understand what it would mean if Donald Trump were back in the White House with no guardrails.
因为我们现在知道法院不会阻止他。
Because certainly we know now the court won't stop him.
我们知道J.D.范斯不会阻止他。
We know J.D.
这一切都取决于美国人民。
Vance is not going to stop him.
副总统哈里斯。
It's up to the American people.
谢谢。
Vice President Harris.
林赛？
Thank you.
副总统哈里斯，在您上一次竞选总统时。
Lindsey?
这是她在武器化，而不是我。
Vice President Harris, in your last run for president.
她是武器化的。
This is the one that weaponized, not me.
我可能因为他们对我说的事情而遭受了重创。
She weaponized.
这就是我所经历的。
I probably took a bullet to the head because of the things that they say about me.
我对这些指控感到非常震惊。
They talk about democracy.
他们谈论民主。
I'm a threat to democracy.
我是民主的威胁。
They're the threat to democracy with a fake Russia, Russia, Russia investigation that went nowhere.
他们才是真正的威胁，伪造的“俄罗斯、俄罗斯、俄罗斯”调查毫无结果。
We have a lot to get to.
我们有很多事情要讨论。
Lindsey?
林赛？
Vice President Harris, in your last run for president, you said you wanted to ban fracking.
哈里斯副总统，在你上次竞选总统时，你说你想禁止水力压裂。
Now you don't.
现在你不想这样了。
You wanted mandatory government buyback programs for assault weapons.
你曾希望强制政府回购攻击性武器。
Now your campaign says you don't.
现在你的竞选团队说你不想这样。
You supported decriminalizing border crossings.
你支持非刑事化边境跨越。
Now you're taking a harder line.
现在你采取了更强硬的立场。
I know you say that your values have not changed.
我知道你说你的价值观没有改变。
So then why have so many of your policy positions changed?
那么，为什么你的许多政策立场发生了变化？
So my values have not changed, and I'm going to discuss every one of the – at least every point that you've made.
我的价值观没有改变，我会讨论你提到的每一个点。
But in particular, let's talk about fracking, because we're here in Pennsylvania.
但特别是，让我们谈谈水力压裂，因为我们在宾夕法尼亚州。
I made that very clear in 2020.
我在2020年时就已明确表示。
I will not ban fracking.
我不会禁止水力压裂。
I have not banned fracking as vice president of the United States.
作为美国副总统，我没有禁止水力压裂。
And in fact, I was the tie-breaking vote on the Inflation Reduction Act, which opened new leases for fracking.
实际上，我在《通货膨胀削减法案》中投下了打破僵局的一票，该法案为水力压裂开放了新租约。
My position is that we have got to invest in diverse sources of energy so we reduce our reliance on foreign oil.
我的立场是，我们必须投资于多样化的能源来源，以减少对外国石油的依赖。
We have had the largest increase in domestic oil production in history because of an approach that recognizes that we cannot over-rely on foreign oil.
由于一种认识到我们不能过度依赖外国石油的方法，我们实现了历史上国内石油生产的最大增长。
As it relates to my values, let me tell you, I grew up a middle-class kid raised by a hardworking mother.
关于我的价值观，让我告诉你，我是一个中产阶级孩子，由一位勤劳的母亲抚养长大。
who worked and saved and was able to buy our first home when I was a teenager.
她努力工作并节省，能够在我十几岁时买下我们的第一套房子。
The values I bring to the importance of home ownership, knowing not everybody got handed $400 million on a silver platter and then filed bankruptcy six times.
我所带来的价值观是重视房屋拥有权，知道并不是每个人都能轻易获得4亿美元的财富，然后破产六次。
is a value that I bring to my work to say we are going to work with the private sector and home builders to increase 3 million homes, increase by 3 million homes by the end of my first term.
这是我在工作中所带来的价值观，表明我们将与私营部门和房屋建设者合作，到我第一任期结束时增加300万套住房。
My work that is related to having a friend when I was in high school who was sexually assaulted by her stepfather.
我的工作与我在高中时有一个朋友，她被继父性侵有关。
And my focus then on protecting women and children from violent crime is based on a value that is deeply grounded in the importance of standing up for those who are most vulnerable.
我当时关注保护女性和儿童免受暴力犯罪的工作，是基于对保护最脆弱者的重要性的深厚价值观。
My work that is about protecting Social Security and Medicare is based on long-standing work that I have done protecting seniors from scams.
我保护社会保障和医疗保险的工作，是基于我长期以来保护老年人免受诈骗的努力。
My values have not changed.
我的价值观没有改变。
And what is important is that there is a president who actually brings values and a perspective that is about lifting people up and not beating people down and name-calling.
重要的是，有一位总统实际上带来了提升人们的价值观和视角，而不是打压人们和辱骂。
The true measure of the leader is the leader who actually understands the strength is not in beating people down, it's in lifting people up.
一个领导者真正的衡量标准在于，他真正理解力量不是在于压制他人，而在于提升他人。
I intend to be that president.
我打算成为这样的总统。
President Trump, your response?
特朗普总统，您的回应？
Well, first of all, I wasn't given $400 million.
首先，我没有得到四亿美金。
I wish I was.
我希望我能得到。
My father was a Brooklyn builder, Brooklyn Queens, and a great father, and I learned a lot from him.
我的父亲是布鲁克林的建筑商，布鲁克林皇后区的一位伟大父亲，我从他身上学到了很多。
But I was given a fraction of that, a tiny fraction, and I built it into many, many billions of dollars, many, many billions.
但我得到的只是其中的一小部分，微不足道的一部分，我把它发展成了许多亿美金，许多亿。
And when people see it, they are even surprised.
当人们看到这一点时，他们甚至感到惊讶。
So we don't have to talk about that.
所以我们不必谈论这个。
Fracking?
水力压裂？
She's been against it for 12 years.
她反对这个已经12年了。
Defund the police?
削减警察经费？
She's been against that forever.
她对此一直反对。
She gave all that stuff up.
她放弃了所有那些立场。
Very wrongly very horribly and everybody's laughing at it.
非常错误，非常可怕，大家都在嘲笑她。
Okay, they're all laughing at it She gave up at least 12 and probably 14 or 15 different policies like she was big on defund the police in Minnesota She went out.
好吧，他们都在嘲笑她，她放弃了至少12个，可能14或15个不同的政策，比如她在明尼苏达州大力支持削减警察经费。她出去。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
I'm talking now If you don't mind, please Does that sound familiar?
我现在在说话，如果您不介意，请。听起来熟悉吗？
She went out
她出去
She went out in Minnesota and wanted to let criminals that killed people, that burned down Minneapolis, she went out and raised money to get them out of jail.
她在明尼苏达州，想要让那些杀人、纵火烧毁明尼阿波利斯的罪犯，她出去筹款让他们出狱。
She did things that nobody would ever think of.
她做了没人会想到的事情。
Now she wants to do transgender operations on illegal aliens that are in prison.
现在她想要对监狱中的非法移民进行变性手术。
This is a radical left liberal that would do this.
这是一个会这样做的激进左派自由派。
She wants to confiscate your guns, and she will never allow fracking in Pennsylvania.
她想要没收你的枪支，而且她永远不会允许在宾夕法尼亚州进行水力压裂。
If she won the election, fracking in Pennsylvania will end on day one.
如果她赢得选举，宾夕法尼亚州的水力压裂将在第一天结束。
Just to finish, one thing, so important in my opinion.
最后要补充一点，在我看来，这一点非常重要。
So I got the oil business going like nobody has ever done before.
所以我让石油业务运转得前所未有。
They took, when they took over, they got rid of it, started getting rid of it, and the prices were going up the roof.
他们接管后，开始逐步淘汰，价格飙升。
They immediately let these guys go to where they were.
他们立刻让这些人回到他们原来的地方。
I would have been five times, four times, five times higher, because you're talking about three and a half years ago.
我本可以比现在高出四到五倍，因为你说的是三年半前。
They got it up to where I was because they had no choice, because the prices of energy were quadrupling and doubling.
他们把它提高到我所在的地方，因为他们别无选择，因为能源价格翻了四倍和两倍
You saw what happened to gasoline.
你看到汽油发生了什么
So they said, let's go back to Trump.
所以他们说，让我们回到特朗普
But if she won the election the day after that election,
但是如果她赢得了选举，选举后的第二天
They'll go back to destroying our country, and oil will be dead, fossil fuel will be dead.
他们将会回去摧毁我们的国家，石油将会消亡，化石燃料将会消亡
We'll go back to windmills, and we'll go back to solar, where they need a whole desert to get some energy to come out of.
我们将回到风力发电，我们将回到太阳能，他们需要整片沙漠才能获取一些能量
You ever see a solar plant?
你见过太阳能电厂吗
By the way, I'm a big fan of solar.
顺便说一下，我是太阳能的忠实支持者
But they take
但它们需要
400, 500 acres of desert soil.
400、500英亩的沙漠土地
These are not good things for the environment, as she understands.
这些对环境并不是好事，她是明白的
Thank you.
谢谢
Lindsey, thank you.
林赛，谢谢
We have an election in just 56 days.
我们还有56天就要选举了
And I want to talk about the peaceful transfer of power, which of course we all know is a cornerstone of our democracy and the role of a president in a moment of crisis.
我想谈谈和平的权力移交，当然我们都知道这是我们民主的基石，以及总统在危机时刻的角色
Mr. President, on January 6th, you told your supporters to march to the Capitol.
总统先生，在1月6日，您告诉您的支持者前往国会大厦
You said you would be right there with them.
您说您会和他们在一起
The country and the world saw what played out at the Capitol that day, the officers coming under attack.
国家和世界看到那天在国会大厦发生的事情，警察遭到攻击
Aides in the West Wing say you watched it unfold on television off the Oval Office.
西翼的助手说您在椭圆形办公室外的电视上观看了这一切
You did send out tweets, but it was more than two hours before you sent out that video message telling your supporters to go home.
您确实发了推特，但在您发出那条视频信息告诉您的支持者回家的时候，已经过了两个多小时
Is there anything you regret about what you did on that day?
您对那天您所做的事情有任何后悔吗
You just said a thing that isn't covered.
您刚才说的事情并没有被报道
Peacefully and patriotically, I said during my speech, not later on.
我在演讲中说过是和平和爱国地，而不是后来
Peacefully and patriotically.
和平和爱国地
And nobody on the other side was killed.
而且对方没有人被杀
Ashley Babbitt was shot by an out of control police officer that should have never
阿什莉·巴比特是被一名失控的警察射杀的，他根本不应该
ever shot her.
射杀她
It's a disgrace.
这是一种耻辱
But we didn't do this group of people that have been treated so badly.
但我们没有对这群受到如此对待的人做这样的事情
I ask, what about all the people that are pouring into our country and killing people that she allowed to pour in?
我想问，所有涌入我们国家并杀人那些她允许涌入的人怎么办
She was the borders are remember that she was the borders are she doesn't want to be called the borders are because she's embarrassed by the border.
她是边境事务大臣，记住，她是边境事务大臣，她不想被称为边境事务大臣，因为她对边境感到尴尬。
In fact, she said at the beginning, Well, I'm surprised you're not talking about the border yet.
事实上，她一开始就说，嗯，我很惊讶你还没有谈论边境问题。
That's because she knows what a bad job they've done.
那是因为她知道他们做得有多糟糕。
What about those people?
那些人呢？
What are they gonna be prosecuted?
他们会被起诉吗？
When are these people from countries all over the world, not just South America, they're coming in from all over the world, David, all over the world, and crime rates are down all over the world because of it.
这些来自世界各地的人，不仅仅是南美洲，他们是从世界各地而来，大卫，来自世界各地，犯罪率因此而下降。
But one of those, David, when are those people gonna be prosecuted?
但是大卫，那些人什么时候会被起诉？
When are the people that burned down Minneapolis gonna be prosecuted?
那些烧毁明尼阿波利斯的人什么时候会被起诉？
Or in Seattle, they went into Seattle, they took over a big percentage of the city of Seattle.
或者在西雅图，他们进入西雅图，占领了西雅图的大部分地区。
When are those people gonna be prosecuted?
那些人什么时候会被起诉？
But let me just ask you.
但让我问你一下。
You might ask her that question.
你可能问她这个问题。
You were the president.
你是总统。
You were watching it unfold on television.
你在电视上看着这一切展开。
It's a very simple question as we move forward toward another election.
这是一个非常简单的问题，随着我们朝另一次选举迈进。
Is there anything you regret about what you did on that day?
关于那一天你所做的事情，有什么遗憾吗？
I had nothing to do with that other than they asked me to make a speech.
我与此无关，除了他们让我发表演讲。
I showed up for a speech.
我去发表了演讲。
I said, I think it's going to be big.
我说，我认为这将会很盛大。
I went to Nancy Pelosi and the mayor of Washington, D.C., and the mayor put it back in writing, as you know.
我去找南希·佩洛西和华盛顿特区的市长，市长如你所知，将其写了下来。
I said, you know, this is going to be a very big rally or whatever you want to call it.
我说，你知道，这将会是一个非常大的集会，或者你想称之为其他什么。
And again, it wasn't done by me.
而且，这不是我做的。
It was done by others.
这是别人做的。
I said, I'd like to give you 10,000 National Guard or soldiers.
我说，我想给你们提供1万名国民警卫队或士兵。
They rejected me.
他们拒绝了我。
Nancy Pelosi rejected me.
南希·佩洛西拒绝了我。
It was just two weeks ago.
就在两周前。
Her daughter has a tape of her saying she is fully responsible for what happened.
她的女儿有一段录像，录像中她说她对发生的事情完全负责。
They want to get rid of that tape.
他们想要销毁那段录像。
It would have never happened if Nancy Pelosi and the mayor of Washington did their jobs.
如果南希·佩洛西和华盛顿市长履行了他们的职责，这一切都不会发生。
I wasn't responsible for security.
我并不负责安全。
Nancy Pelosi was responsible.
南希·佩洛西负责。
She didn't do her job.
她没有尽到自己的职责。
The question was about you as president, not about former Speaker Pelosi.
问题是关于你作为总统的，而不是前议长佩洛西的。
But I do want Vice President Harris to respond here.
但我确实希望哈里斯副总统在这里做出回应。
I was at the Capitol on January 6th.
我在1月6日那天在国会大厦。
I was the vice president-elect.
我当时是当选副总统。
I was also an acting senator.
我也是一名代理参议员。
I was there.
我在那里。
And on that day, the President of the United States incited a violent mob to attack our nation's Capitol, to desecrate our nation's Capitol.
在那一天，美国总统煽动了一群暴徒攻击我们国家的国会大厦，亵渎了我们国家的国会大厦。
On that day, 140 law enforcement officers were injured, and some died.
在那一天，140名执法人员受伤，还有一些人丧生。
And understand, the former president has been indicted and impeached for exactly that reason.
请理解，前总统正是因为这个原因被起诉和弹劾。
But this is not an isolated situation.
但这并不是孤立的事件。
Let's remember Charlottesville, where there was a mob of people carrying tiki torches, spewing anti-Semitic hate.
让我们记住夏洛茨维尔，当时有一群人举着火把，散布反犹太主义的仇恨。
And what did the president then at the time say?
那么当时的总统说了什么呢？
There were fine people on each side.
两边都有很优秀的人。
Let's remember.
让我们记住。
that when it came to the Proud Boys, a militia, the president said, the former president said, stand back and stand by.
当谈到骄傲男孩这个民兵组织时，前总统说，退后并待命。
So for everyone watching who remembers what January 6th was, I say we don't have to go back.
所以对于所有观看的人，记得1月6日是什么，我说我们不必回头。
Let's not go back.
让我们不要回头。
We're not going back.
我们不会回头。
It's time to turn the page.
是时候翻开新的一页了。
And if that was a bridge too far for you, well, there is a place in our campaign for you to stand for country, to stand for our democracy, to stand for rule of law, and to end the chaos
如果这对你来说是一个过于严苛的要求，那么在我们的竞选中有一个地方可以让你为国家而站立，为我们的民主而站立，为法治而站立，结束混乱
and to end the approach that is about attacking the foundations of our democracy, because you don't like the outcome.
并结束那种攻击我们民主基础的方法，因为你不喜欢结果。
And be clear on that point.
对此要明确。
Donald Trump, the candidate, has said in this election there will be a bloodbath if this and the outcome of this election is not to his liking.
唐纳德·特朗普，作为候选人，在这次选举中表示，如果这次选举的结果不符合他的意愿，将会是一场血腥的屠杀。
Let's turn the page on this.
让我们翻开新的一页。
Let's not go back.
让我们不要回头。
Let's chart a course for the future and not go backwards to the past.
让我们为未来制定一个方向，而不是倒退到过去。
Let me just follow up here.
让我在这里补充一下。
It was a different term, and it was a term that related to energy, because they have destroyed our energy business.
这是一个不同的任期，涉及到能源，因为他们摧毁了我们的能源产业。
That was where Bloodbath was.
那就是“血腥屠杀”的地方。
Also, on Charlottesville, that story has been, as you would say, debunked.
此外，关于夏洛茨维尔，那则故事已经被你们称之为揭穿了。
Laura Ingram,
劳拉·英格拉姆，
Sean Hannity, Jesse, all of these people, they covered it.
肖恩·汉尼蒂，杰西，所有这些人，他们都进行了报道。
If they go an extra sentence, they will see it was perfect.
如果他们多说一句话，他们会发现这一切是完美的。
It was debunked in almost every newspaper, but they still bring it up, just like they bring 2025 up.
几乎所有的报纸都揭穿了这一点，但他们仍然提起，就像他们提起2025一样。
They bring all of this stuff up.
他们提起所有这些事情。
I ask you this, you talk about the Capitol.
我问你们，你们谈论国会大厦。
Why are we allowing these millions of people to come through on the southern border?
为什么我们允许这些数百万人通过南部边界进入？
How come she's not doing anything?
她为什么不采取任何行动？
And I'll tell you what I would do, and I would be very proud to do it.
我告诉你我会怎么做，我会很自豪地去做。
I would say we would both leave this debate right now.
我会说我们两个现在就离开这个辩论。
I'd like to see her go down
我想看看她去
to Washington D.C.
华盛顿特区。
during this debate, because we're wasting a lot of time, go down to, because she's been so bad, it's so ridiculous, go down to Washington D.C.
在这个辩论期间，因为我们浪费了很多时间，去吧，因为她表现得太糟糕，太荒谬，去华盛顿特区。
and let her sign a bill to close up the border.
让她签署一项关闭边界的法案。
Because they have the right to do it.
因为他们有权这样做。
They don't need bills.
他们不需要法案。
They have the right to do it.
他们有权这样做。
The President of the United States, you'll get him out of bed, you'll wake him up at 4 o'clock in the afternoon, you'll say, come on, come on down to the office, let's sign a bill.
美国总统，你把他叫起床，你在下午四点把他叫醒，你会说，来吧，来办公室，让我们签署一项法案。
If he signs a bill that the border is closed, all he has to do is say it to the border patrol, who are phenomenal.
如果他签署一项关闭边界的法案，他所需要做的就是告诉边境巡逻队，他们非常出色。
If they do that, the border is closed.
如果他们这样做，边界就关闭了。
Those people are killing many people, unlike J6.
那些人正在杀死很多人，不像J6。
We talked immigration here tonight.
我们今晚谈论移民。
I do want to focus on this next issue to both of you, because it really brings us, this into focus, truth in these times that we're living in.
我确实想关注下一个问题，因为这真的让我们聚焦在我们生活的这个时代的真相上。
Mr. President, for three and a half years after you lost the 2020 election, you repeatedly falsely claimed that you won, many times saying you won in a landslide.
总统先生，在你失去2020年选举后的三年半里，你多次错误地声称你赢了，很多次说你是以压倒性胜利获胜的。
In the past couple of weeks leading up to this debate, you have said, quote, you lost by a whisker, that you, quote, didn't quite make it, that you came up a little bit short.
在这次辩论前的几周里，你说过，你以微弱差距输掉，称你“没能成功”，你有点落后。
I said that?
我说过吗？
Are you now acknowledging that you lost in 2020?
你现在承认你在2020年输了？
No, I don't acknowledge that at all.
不，我根本不承认这一点
But you did say that.
但你确实说过。
I said that sarcastically.
我那是讽刺地说的。
You know that.
你知道的。
We said, oh, we lost by a whisker.
我们说，哦，我们差一点就输了。
That was said sarcastically.
那是讽刺地说的。
There's so much proof.
有很多证据。
All you have to do is look at it.
你只需要看看就知道。
And they should have sent it back to the legislatures for approval.
他们应该把它送回立法机构批准。
I got almost 75 million votes, the most votes any sitting president has ever gotten.
我得到了近7500万票，这是任何现任总统获得的最多选票。
I was told if I got 63, which was what I got in 2016, you can't be beaten.
我被告知如果我得到63万票（就是我在2016年得到的），你就无法被击败。
The election people should never be thinking about an election is fraudulent.
选举人员绝不应该认为选举是欺诈的。
We need two things.
我们需要两件事。
We need walls We need and we have to have it.
我们需要墙，我们必须有它。
We have to have borders and we have to have good elections Our elections are bad and a lot of these illegal immigrants coming in.
我们必须有边界，我们必须有良好的选举。我们的选举很糟糕，很多非法移民进来。
They're trying to get them to vote.
他们试图让他们投票。
They can't even speak English They don't even know what country they're in practically and these people are trying to get them to vote and that's why they're allowing Them to come into our country
他们甚至不会说英语，几乎不知道自己在哪个国家，这些人试图让他们投票，这就是为什么他们允许他们进入我们的国家。
You should watch all of these pieces of video.
你应该看看所有这些视频片段。
I didn't detect the sarcasm.
我没有察觉到讽刺。
Lost by a whisker.
差一点就输了。
We didn't quite make it.
我们没能成功。
And we should just point out here, as clarification, and you know this, you and your allies, 60 cases in front of many judges, many of them Republican, and said there was no widespread fraud.
我们应该在这里指出，作为澄清，而你知道的，你和你的盟友，60个案件在许多法官面前，其中许多是共和党人，他们说没有广泛的欺诈。
No judge looked at it.
没有法官审视过。
They said we didn't have standing.
他们说我们没有立场。
That's the other thing.
这就是另一件事。
They said we didn't have standing, a technicality.
他们说我们没有立场，这是一个技术性问题。
Can you imagine a system where a person in an election doesn't have standing?
你能想象一个系统，在选举中一个人没有立场吗？
The President of the United States doesn't have standing.
美国总统没有立场。
That's how we lost.
这就是我们失败的原因。
If you look at the facts, and I'd love to have you do a special on it,
如果你看看事实，我很想让你做一个特别节目。
I'll show you Georgia, and I'll show you Wisconsin, and I'll show you Pennsylvania, and I'll show you — we have so many facts and statistics.
我会给你展示乔治亚州，我会给你展示威斯康星州，我会给你展示宾夕法尼亚州，我会给你展示——我们有很多事实和统计数据。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
That doesn't matter, because we have to solve the problem that we have right now.
这没关系，因为我们必须解决当前面临的问题。
That's old news.
那是旧闻。
And the problem that we have right now is we have a nation in decline, and they have put it into decline.
而我们现在面临的问题是，我们的国家正在衰退，而他们使其走向衰退。
We have a nation that is dying, David.
我们有一个正在走向灭亡的国家，大卫。
Mr. President, thank you.
总统先生，谢谢您。
Vice President Harris, you heard the president there tonight.
哈里斯副总统，您今晚听到了总统的发言。
He said he didn't say that, that he lost by a whisker.
他说他没有说过，他是以微弱的差距输掉的。
So he still believes he did not lose the election that was won by President Biden and yourself.
所以他仍然相信他没有输掉由拜登总统和您赢得的选举。
But I do want to ask you about something that's come up in the last couple of days.
但我确实想问您一些最近几天出现的事情。
This was a post from President Trump.
这是特朗普总统的一条帖子。
about this upcoming election just weeks away.
关于即将到来的选举，仅仅几周后。
He said, when I win, those people who cheated, and then he lists donors, voters, election officials, he says, will be prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law, which will include long-term prison sentences.
他说，当我赢的时候，那些作弊的人，接着他列出了捐赠者、选民和选举官员，他说，他们将受到法律的最严厉制裁，包括长期监禁。
One of your campaign's top lawyers responded, saying, we won't let Donald Trump intimidate us.
您竞选团队的一位首席律师回应说，我们不会让唐纳德·特朗普威胁我们。
We won't let him suppress the vote.
我们不会让他压制投票。
Is that what you believe he's trying to do here?
您认为他在这里试图这样做吗？
Donald Trump was fired by 81 million people.
唐纳德·特朗普被8100万人民解雇了。
So let's be clear about that.
所以我们要明确这一点。
And clearly he is having a very difficult time processing that.
显然，他在处理这一点上非常困难。
But we cannot afford to have a President of the United States who attempts, as he did in the past, to upend the will of the voters in a free and fair election.
但我们不能允许一个试图，如他过去所做的那样，颠覆自由公正选举中选民意志的美国总统。
And I'm going to tell you that I have traveled the world as Vice President of the United States, and world leaders are laughing at Donald Trump.
我想告诉你，作为美国副总统，我已经走遍了世界，世界领导人正在嘲笑唐纳德·特朗普。
I have talked with military leaders, some of whom worked with you, and they say you're a disgrace.
我与一些曾与您合作的军事领导人交谈过，他们说您是个耻辱。
And when you then talk in this way in a presidential debate and deny what over and over again are court cases you have lost because you did in fact lose that election, it leads one to believe that perhaps we do not have in the candidate to my right the temperament
而当您在总统辩论中以这样的方式发言，并否认那些您因确实输掉选举而反复失利的法庭案件时，这让人相信，也许我们右侧的候选人缺乏
or the ability to not be confused about fact.
或能力不被事实混淆。
That's deeply troubling, and the American people deserve better.
这非常令人不安，而美国人民应得更好的。
I'll give you one minute to respond, Mr. President.
我给您一分钟的时间回应，总统先生。
Let me just tell you about world leaders.
让我告诉您一些关于世界领导人的事。
Viktor Orban, one of the most respected men.
维克托·欧尔班，是最受尊敬的人之一。
They call him a strong man.
他们称他为强人。
He's a tough person.
他是一个强硬的人
Smart.
聪明
Prime Minister of Hungary.
匈牙利总理
They said, why is the whole world blowing up?
他们说，为什么整个世界都在动荡？
Three years ago, it wasn't.
三年前，情况并不是这样
Why is it blowing up?
为什么会动荡？
He said, because you need Trump back as president.
他说，因为你需要特朗普重新担任总统
They were afraid of him.
他们害怕他
China was afraid.
中国害怕
And I don't like to use the word afraid, but I'm just quoting him.
我不喜欢用“害怕”这个词，但我只是引用他的话
China was afraid of him.
中国害怕他
North Korea was afraid of him.
朝鲜也害怕他
Look at what's going on with North Korea, by the way.
顺便说一下，看看朝鲜发生了什么
He said Russia was afraid of him.
他说俄罗斯也害怕他
I ended the Nord Stream 2 pipeline and Biden put it back on day one, but he ended the XL pipeline.
我结束了北溪2号管道，而拜登在第一天就让它重新启用，但他却结束了XL管道
The XL pipeline in our country, he ended that, but he let the Russians build a pipeline going all over Europe and heading into Germany, the biggest pipeline in the world.
在我们国家，他结束了XL管道，但却让俄罗斯建造了一条横贯整个欧洲并通往德国的管道，世界上最大的管道
Look.
看看
Victor Orban said it.
维克托·欧尔班说过
He said the most respected, most feared person is Donald Trump.
他说，最受尊敬、最令人畏惧的人是唐纳德·特朗普
We had no problems when Trump was president.
当特朗普担任总统时，我们没有任何问题
But when this weak, pathetic man that you saw at a debate just a few months ago, that if he weren't in that debate, he'd be running instead of her.
但是当你在几个月前看到的那个软弱、可怜的人出现在辩论中时，如果他不在辩论中，他将会比她更有竞争力
She got no votes.
她得不到任何选票
He got 14 million votes.
他得到了1400万选票
What you did, you talk about a threat to democracy.
你所做的，就是谈论对民主的威胁
He got 14 million votes and they threw him out of office.
他得到了1400万选票，他们却把他赶出了办公室
And you know what?
你知道吗？
I'll give you a little secret.
我给你一个小秘密
He hates her.
他恨她
He can't stand her.
他无法忍受她
But he got 14 million votes.
但他得到了1400万选票
They threw him out.
他们把他赶了出去。
She got zero votes.
她得了零票。
And when she ran, she was the first one to leave because she failed.
当她参选时，她是第一个因为失败而退场的。
And now she's running.
而现在她又在竞选。
I don't understand it, but I'm okay with it because...
我不理解，但我对此无所谓，因为...
Your time is up.
你的时间到了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I think we're going to do very well.
我觉得我们会做得很好。
We've got a lot more to get to.
我们还有很多事情要处理。
Turning now to the Israel-Hamas war and the hostages who are still being held, Americans among them.
现在转向以色列-哈马斯战争，以及仍被扣为人质的情况，其中包括美国人。
Vice President Harris, in December you said, quote, Israel has a right to defend itself.
哈里斯副总统，您在十二月曾说过，引用，   以色列有权自卫。
But you added, quote, it matters how, saying international humanitarian law must be respected.
但您补充说，引用，   这要看如何做，必须尊重国际人道主义法。
Israel must do more to protect innocent civilians.
以色列必须采取更多措施来保护无辜平民。
You said that nine months ago.
您九个月前是这样说的。
Now an estimated 40,000 Palestinians are dead.
现在估计已有四万名巴勒斯坦人死亡。
Nearly 100 hostages remain.
近百名人质仍然被扣留。
Just last week, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said there's not a deal in the making.
就在上周，内塔尼亚胡总理表示没有达成协议。
President Biden has not been able to break through the stalemate.
拜登总统未能打破僵局。
How would you do it?
您会如何做？
Well, let's understand how we got here.
好吧，让我们了解一下我们是如何走到这一步的。
On October 7, Hamas, a terrorist organization,
在十月七日，哈马斯，一个恐怖组织，   屠杀了1200名以色列人，许多都是仅仅参加音乐会的年轻人。
slaughtered 1,200 Israelis, many of them young people who were simply attending a concert.
女性遭受到可怕的强奸。
Women were horribly raped.
所以我绝对在那时说过，现在也说，以色列有权自卫。
And so absolutely, I said then, I say now, Israel has a right to defend itself.
我们也会这样做。
We would.
而且它如何自卫非常重要，因为同样也有太多无辜的巴勒斯坦人被杀。
And how it does so matters, because it is also true far too many innocent Palestinians have been killed.
儿童，母亲。
Children, mothers.
我们知道这场战争必须结束。
What we know is that this war must end.
它必须立即结束，结束的方式是我们需要达成停火协议，并且需要释放人质。
It must end immediately, and the way it will end is we need a ceasefire deal and we need the hostages out.
因此我们将继续不分昼夜地为此努力。
And so we will continue to work around the clock on that.
我们将继续推动这一进程。
Work around the clock also understanding that we must chart a course for a two-state solution.
我们必须全力以赴，同时理解我们必须为两国解决方案制定路线图
And in that solution, there must be security for the Israeli people and Israel and an equal measure for the Palestinians.
在这个解决方案中，必须为以色列人民和以色列提供安全，同时也为巴勒斯坦人提供同等的保障
But the one thing I will assure you always, I will always give Israel the ability to defend itself, in particular as it relates to Iran and any threat that Iran and its proxies pose to Israel.
但我可以向你们保证，我将始终给予以色列自我防卫的能力，特别是在与伊朗及其代理人对以色列构成威胁时
But we must have a two-state solution where we can rebuild Gaza, where the Palestinians have security, self-determination, and the dignity they so rightly deserve.
但我们必须有一个两国解决方案，在那里我们可以重建加沙，巴勒斯坦人拥有安全、自决权和他们应得的尊严
President Trump, how would you negotiate with Netanyahu and also Hamas in order to get the hostages out and prevent the killing of more innocent civilians in Gaza?
特朗普总统，您将如何与内塔尼亚胡以及哈马斯谈判，以解救人质并防止更多无辜平民在加沙被杀？
If I were president, it would have never started.
如果我是总统，这一切根本不会发生
If I were president, Russia would have never, ever, I know Putin very well, he would have never, and there was no threat of it either, by the way, for four years, have gone into Ukraine and killed millions of people when you add it up.
如果我是总统，俄罗斯绝不会，我非常了解普京，他绝对不会，而且在过去四年里也没有任何威胁，进入乌克兰并造成数百万人的死亡
Far worse than people understand what's going on over there.
情况远比人们理解的要糟糕得多
But when she mentions about Israel, all of a sudden, she hates Israel.
但当她提到以色列时，突然间，她就讨厌以色列
She wouldn't even meet with Netanyahu when he went to Congress to make a very important speech.
当内塔尼亚胡来到国会发表重要演讲时，她甚至不愿与他见面
She refused to be there because she was at a sorority party of hers.
她拒绝出席，因为她在参加她的姐妹会聚会
She wanted to go to the sorority party.
她想去姐妹会聚会
She hates Israel.
她讨厌以色列
If she's president, I believe that Israel will not exist within two years from now.
如果她成为总统，我相信以色列将在两年内不复存在
And I've been pretty good at predictions, and I hope I'm wrong about that one.
我在预测方面一直表现不错，我希望我在这一点上是错的
She hates Israel.
她讨厌以色列
At the same time, in her own way, she hates the Arab population, because the whole place is going to get blown up.
与此同时，以她自己的方式，她也讨厌阿拉伯人，因为整个地方将会被摧毁
Arabs, Jewish people, Israel.
阿拉伯人、犹太人、以色列
Israel will be gone.
以色列将会消失
It would have never happened.
这一切根本不会发生
Iran was broke under Donald Trump.
在唐纳德·特朗普执政期间，伊朗是破产的
Now Iran has $300 billion because they took off all the sanctions that I had.
现在伊朗有了3000亿美元，因为他们解除我施加的所有制裁
Iran had no money for Hamas or Hezbollah or any of the 28 different spheres of terror.
伊朗没有钱给哈马斯或真主党，或任何28个不同的恐怖领域
And they are spheres of terror, horrible terror.
而且它们确实是恐怖领域，糟糕的恐怖
They had no money.
他们没有钱
It was a big story, and you know it.
这是一个大新闻，你知道的
You covered it very well, actually.
实际上，你们报道得很好
They had no money for terror.
他们没有钱用于恐怖活动
They were broke.
他们是破产的
Now they're a rich nation.
现在他们是一个富裕的国家
And now what they're doing is they're spreading that money around.
他们现在所做的就是把那些钱分散出去。
Look at what's happening with the Houthis and Yemen.
看看胡塞武装和也门的局势。
Look at what's going on in the Middle East.
看看中东发生的事情。
This would have never happened.
这一切是绝对不会发生的。
I will get that settled and fast, and I'll get the war with Ukraine and Russia ended.
我会迅速解决这个问题，并结束乌克兰与俄罗斯的战争。
If I'm president-elect, I'll get it done before even becoming president.
如果我当选总统，我会在上任之前就完成这件事。
Vice President Harris, he says you hate Israel.
哈里斯副总统，他说你讨厌以色列。
That's absolutely not true.
这绝对不是真的。
I have my entire career and life supported Israel and the Israeli people.
我在整个职业生涯和生活中都支持以色列和以色列人民。
He knows that.
他知道这一点。
He's trying to again divide and distract
他又在试图分裂和转移注意力
from the reality, which is it is very well known that Donald Trump is weak and wrong on national security and foreign policy.
以掩盖事实，众所周知，唐纳德·特朗普在国家安全和外交政策上是软弱和错误的。
It is well known that he admires dictators, wants to be a dictator on day one according to himself.
众所周知，他崇拜独裁者，自己也想在第一天就成为独裁者。
It is well known that he said of Putin that he can do whatever the hell he wants and go into Ukraine.
众所周知，他曾说普京可以随心所欲地进入乌克兰。
It is well known that he said when Russia went into Ukraine, it was brilliant.
众所周知，他曾说俄罗斯进入乌克兰时，这真是太聪明了。
It is well known he exchanged love letters with Kim Jong-un.
众所周知，他和金正恩互换了情书。
And it is absolutely well known that these dictators and autocrats are rooting for you to be president again, because they're so clear they can manipulate you with flattery and favors.
而且绝对众所周知，这些独裁者和专制者希望你再次成为总统，因为他们清楚可以用奉承和恩惠来操控你。
And that is why
这就是为什么
So many military leaders who you have worked with have told me you are a disgrace.
你曾合作过的许多军事领导人告诉我你是个耻辱。
That is why we understand that we have to have a president who is not consistently weak and wrong on national security, including the importance of upholding and respecting in highest regard our military.
这就是为什么我们明白，我们需要一位在国家安全问题上不是一贯软弱和错误的总统，尤其是要高度重视和尊重我们的军队。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢。
And she's the one that caused it.
而她就是导致这一切的人。
That's weak on national security by allowing every nation last month for the year 168 different countries sending people into our country.
这在国家安全上是软弱的，允许去年168个不同国家的人进入我们的国家。
Their crime weights are way down.
他们的犯罪率大幅下降。
Putin endorsed her last week said I hope she wins and I think he meant it.
普京上周支持她说我希望她赢，我认为他是认真的。
because what he's gotten away with is absolutely incredible.
因为他所逃避的事情绝对令人难以置信。
It wouldn't have happened with me.
在我这里是不会发生的。
The leaders of other countries think that they're weak and incompetent, and they are.
其他国家的领导人认为他们软弱无能，确实如此。
They're grossly incompetent.
他们极其无能。
And I just ask one question.
我只问一个问题。
Why does Biden go in and kill the Keystone pipeline and approve the single biggest deal that Russia's ever made, Nord Stream 2, the biggest pipeline anywhere in the world going to Germany and all over Europe?
为什么拜登要关闭基斯通管道，却批准俄罗斯有史以来最大的交易——诺德斯特里姆2号，这是通往德国和整个欧洲的最大管道？
because they're weak and they're ineffective.
因为他们软弱无能。
And Biden, by the way, gets paid a lot of money.
顺便提一句，拜登赚了很多钱。
Thank you.
谢谢。
We have a lot of issues to get to.
我们有很多问题需要讨论。
We'll be right back with much more of this historic ABC News presidential debate from the National Constitution Center right here in Philadelphia.
我们将在费城的国家宪法中心继续这场历史性的ABC新闻总统辩论，稍后回来。
Back in a moment.
稍后回来。
The ABC News presidential debate will continue after this.
ABC新闻总统辩论将在此之后继续。
from the National Constitution Center in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
来自宾夕法尼亚州费城的国家宪法中心。
Here again, David Muir and Lindsay Davis.
再次欢迎大卫·穆尔和林赛·戴维斯。
Welcome back to this historic ABC News presidential debate tonight.
欢迎回到今晚这场历史性的ABC新闻总统辩论。
We're going to continue here, and I want to turn to the war in Ukraine.
我们将继续进行，我想转向乌克兰战争。
We're now two and a half years into this conflict.
我们现在已经进入这场冲突两年半。
Mr. President, it has been the position of the Biden administration that we must defend Ukraine from Russia, from Vladimir Putin, to defend their sovereignty, their democracy, that it's in America's best interest to do so, arguing that if Putin wins,
总统先生，拜登政府的立场是，我们必须保护乌克兰免受俄罗斯和普京的侵害，以维护他们的主权和民主，这符合美国的最佳利益，认为如果普京获胜，
He may be emboldened to move even further into other countries.
他可能会更加肆无忌惮地向其他国家扩张。
You have said you would solve this war in 24 hours.
您曾说过，您会在24小时内解决这场战争。
You said so just before the break tonight.
您今晚在休息前刚说过这个。
How exactly would you do that?
您到底会如何做到这一点？
And I want to ask you a very simple question tonight.
我今晚想问您一个非常简单的问题。
Do you want Ukraine to win this war?
您希望乌克兰赢得这场战争吗？
I want the war to stop.
我希望战争停止。
I want to save lives that are being uselessly people being killed by the millions.
我想拯救那些毫无意义地被杀死的生命，数以百万计。
It's the millions.
这是数以百万计。
It's so much worse than the numbers that you're getting, which are fake numbers.
这比您得到的数字要糟糕得多，那些都是假数字。
Look,
听着，
We're in for 250 billion or more because they don't ask Europe, which is a much bigger beneficiary to getting this thing done than we are.
我们已经投入了2500亿美元或更多，因为他们没有要求欧洲，欧洲是获得这项交易的更大受益者。
They're in for 150 billion dollars less because Biden and you don't have the courage to ask Europe like I did with NATO.
他们少投入了1500亿美元，因为拜登和您没有勇气像我对待北约时那样要求欧洲。
They paid billions and billions, hundreds of billions of dollars when I said
当我说，
Either you pay up, or we're not going to protect you anymore.
要么你们支付，要么我们就不再保护你们时，他们支付了数十亿、数百亿美元。
So that's maybe one of the reasons they don't like me as much as they like weak people.
所以这也许是他们不喜欢我而更喜欢软弱之人的原因之一。
But you take a look at what's happening.
但你看看发生了什么。
We're in for $250 to $275 billion.
我们面临着2500亿到2750亿美元的损失。
They're into $100 to $150.
他们面临着100亿到150亿美元的损失。
They should be forced to equalize.
他们应该被迫达到平衡。
With that being said, I want to get the war settled.
话虽如此，我想解决战争问题。
I know Zelensky very well, and I know Putin very well.
我非常了解泽伦斯基，也非常了解普京。
I have a good relationship, and they respect
我与他们关系良好，他们尊重
your president, okay?
你的总统，好吗？
They respect me.
他们尊重我。
They don't respect Biden.
他们不尊重拜登。
How would you respect him?
你怎么会尊重他呢？
Why?
For what reason?
出于什么理由？
He hasn't even made a phone call in two years to Putin, hasn't spoken to anybody.
他在两年内甚至没有给普京打过一个电话，没和任何人交谈过。
They don't even try and get it.
他们甚至都没有尝试去解决这个问题。
That is a war that's dying to be settled.
这是一场急需解决的战争。
I will get it settled before I even become president.
我会在成为总统之前解决这个问题。
If I win, when I'm president-elect, and what I'll do is I'll speak to one, I'll speak to the other, I'll get them together.
如果我赢了，当我成为当选总统时，我会和其中一个谈，和另一个谈，我会让他们聚在一起。
That war would have never happened.
这场战争本来不会发生。
And in fact, when I saw Putin after I left,
事实上，当我离开后见到普京时，
Unfortunately, left because our country has gone to hell.
不幸的是，我离开是因为我们的国家已经糟糕透顶。
But after I left, when I saw him building up soldiers, he did it after I left.
但在我离开后，当我看到他在集结士兵时，他是在我离开后才这么做的。
I said, oh, he must be negotiating.
我说，哦，他一定在谈判。
It must be a good, strong point of negotiation.
这一定是一个良好的、强有力的谈判时机。
Well, it wasn't because Biden had no idea how to talk to him.
结果并不是这样，因为拜登根本不知道怎么和他谈。
He had no idea how to stop it.
他根本不知道怎么阻止这一切。
And now you have millions of people dead and it's only getting worse.
现在你有数百万人死去，情况只在恶化。
And it could lead to World War Three.
这可能导致第三次世界大战。
Don't kid yourself, David.
别自欺欺人，戴维。
We're playing with World War III, and we have a president that we don't even know if he's—where is our president?
我们正在玩弄第三次世界大战，而我们有一个总统，我们甚至不知道他——我们的总统在哪里？
We don't even know if he's a president.
我们甚至不知道他是否是总统
And just to clarify here— They threw him out of a campaign like a dog.
为了澄清一下——他们像扔狗一样把他从竞选中赶了出去
We don't even know.
我们甚至不知道
Is he our president?
他是我们的总统吗
But we have a president— Mr. President— —that doesn't know he's alive.
但我们有一位总统——总统先生——他甚至不知道自己还活着
Your time is up.
你的时间到了
Just to clarify the question.
只是为了澄清这个问题
Do you believe it's in the U.S.
你认为乌克兰赢得这场战争对美国
best interest for Ukraine to win this war, yes or no?
的最佳利益是，是还是不是
I think it's the U.S.
我认为这是美国
best interest to get this war finished and just get it done.
的最佳利益，尽快结束这场战争
Negotiate a deal.
谈判达成协议
Because we have to stop all of these human lives from being destroyed.
因为我们必须阻止所有这些生命被摧毁
I want to take this to Vice President Harris.
我想把这个问题抛给副总统哈里斯
I want to get your thoughts on support for Ukraine in this moment.
我想听听你对当前支持乌克兰的看法
But also, as Commander-in-Chief, if elected, how would you deal with Vladimir Putin?
但作为指挥官，如果当选，你将如何应对弗拉基米尔·普京？
And would it be any different from what we're seeing from President Biden?
这会有什么不同于我们看到的拜登总统的做法吗？
Well, first of all, it's important to remind the former president you're not running against Joe Biden, you're running against me.
首先，重要的是要提醒前总统，你不是在与乔·拜登竞选，你是在与我竞争
I believe the reason that Donald Trump says that this war would be over within 24 hours is because he would just give it up.
我相信唐纳德·特朗普说这场战争将在24小时内结束的原因，是因为他会选择放弃
And that's not who we are as Americans.
这不是我们作为美国人的本色
Let's understand what happened here.
让我们了解这里发生了什么
I actually met with Zelensky a few days before Russia invaded, tried through force to change territorial boundaries, to defy one of the most important international rules and norms, which is the importance of sovereignty and territorial integrity.
在俄罗斯入侵之前的几天，我实际上与泽连斯基会面，试图通过武力改变领土边界，挑战国际上最重要的规则和规范之一，即主权和领土完整的重要性
And I met with President Zelensky.
我与泽连斯基总统会面
I shared with him American intelligence about how he could defend himself.
我向他分享了有关他如何自我防卫的美国情报
Days later, I went to NATO's eastern flank, to Poland and Romania.
几天后，我前往北约的东翼，波兰和罗马尼亚
And through the work that I and others did, we brought 50 countries together to support Ukraine in its righteous defense.
通过我和其他人的努力，我们将50个国家聚集在一起，支持乌克兰进行正义的防卫
And because of our support, because of the air defense, the ammunition, the artillery, the Javelins, the Abrams tanks that we have provided, Ukraine stands as an independent and free country.
因为我们的支持，因为空中防御、弹药、炮兵、标枪导弹、我们提供的艾布拉姆斯坦克，乌克兰作为一个独立和自由的国家屹立不倒
If Donald Trump were president, Putin would be sitting in Kiev right now.
如果唐纳德·特朗普是总统，普京现在就会坐在基辅
And understand what that would mean, because Putin's agenda is not just about Ukraine.
要理解这意味着什么，因为普京的议程不仅仅是关于乌克兰
Understand why the European allies and our NATO allies are so thankful that you are no longer president, and that we understand the importance of the greatest military alliance the world has ever known, which is NATO.
要理解为什么欧洲盟友和我们的北约盟友如此感激你不再是总统，以及我们理解世界上最大的军事联盟——北约的重要性
and what we have done to preserve the ability of Zelensky and the Ukrainians to fight for their independence.
我们所做的就是保留泽连斯基和乌克兰人民为争取独立而战的能力。
Otherwise, Putin would be sitting in Kiev with his eyes on the rest of Europe, starting with Poland.
否则，普京会坐在基辅，目光瞄准整个欧洲，从波兰开始。
And why don't you tell the 800,000 Polish-Americans right here in Pennsylvania how quickly you would give up for the sake of favor and what you think is a friendship with what is known to be a dictator who would eat you for lunch.
你为什么不告诉在宾夕法尼亚的80万波兰裔美国人，你会多快为了所谓的友谊而放弃，和一个众所周知的会把你吃掉的独裁者交朋友？
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢你。
We've heard from both of you on Ukraine tonight.
今晚我们听到了你们两位关于乌克兰的看法。
Afghanistan came up in the last hour.
阿富汗在刚才的一个小时内被提及。
I wanted her to respond to something you said earlier.
我想让她回应你之前说的某些话。
Please, I'll give you a minute here.
请，我给你一分钟时间。
Putin would be sitting in Moscow, and he wouldn't have lost 300,000 men and women, but he would have been sitting in Moscow.
普京会坐在莫斯科，他不会损失30万的男女，但他会坐在莫斯科。
Quiet, please.
请安静。
He would have been sitting in Moscow much happier than he is right now.
他会比现在更开心地坐在莫斯科。
But eventually, you know, he's got a thing that other people don't have.
但最终，你知道，他拥有其他人所没有的东西。
He's got nuclear weapons.
他拥有核武器。
They don't ever talk about that.
他们从来没有谈论过这个。
He's got nuclear weapons.
他拥有核武器。
Nobody ever thinks about that.
没有人会想到这一点。
And eventually, maybe he'll use them, and maybe he hasn't been that threatening.
最终，也许他会使用它们，也许他并没有那么具威胁性。
But he does have that, something we don't even like to talk about.
但他确实拥有这个，我们甚至不愿意谈论。
Nobody likes to talk about it.
没有人愿意谈论这个。
But just so you understand, they sent her to negotiate peace before this war started.
但你要明白，他们在这场战争开始前派她去谈判和平。
Three days later, he went in and he started the war because everything they said was weak and stupid.
三天后，他进攻并发动了战争，因为他们所说的一切都软弱无力和愚蠢。
They said the wrong things.
他们说错了话。
That war should have never started.
那场战争根本不该开始。
She was the emissary.
她是特使。
They sent her in to negotiate with Zelensky and Putin.
他们派她去与泽连斯基和普京谈判。
And she did.
而她确实去做了。
And the war started three days later.
三天后战争就开始了。
And that's the kind of talent we have with her.
这就是我们拥有的她的才能。
She's worse than Biden, in my opinion.
在我看来，她比拜登还糟。
I think he's the worst president in the history of our country.
我认为他是我们国家历史上最差的总统。
She goes down as the worst vice president in the history of our country.
她将被记住为我们国家历史上最差的副总统。
But let me tell you something.
但让我告诉你一件事。
She is a horrible negotiator.
她是个糟糕的谈判者。
They sent her in to negotiate.
他们派她去谈判。
As soon as they left, Putin did the invasion.
一离开，普京就发动了入侵。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢您。
You did bring up something.
您确实提到了某些事情。
You said she went to negotiate with Vladimir Putin.
您说她去与弗拉基米尔·普京谈判。
Vice President Harris, have you ever met Vladimir Putin?
哈里斯副总统，您见过弗拉基米尔·普京吗？
Can you clarify tonight?
今晚您能澄清一下吗？
Yet again, I said at the beginning of this debate, you're going to hear a bunch of lies coming from this fellow.
我在这场辩论开始时就说过，您将听到这个家伙说的一堆谎言。
And that is another one.
这又是一个谎言。
When I went to meet with President Zelensky, I've now met with him over five times.
当我去见泽伦斯基总统时，我现在已经见过他超过五次。
The reality is it has been about standing as America always should, as a leader upholding international rules and norms, as a leader who shows strength, understanding that the alliances we have around the world are dependent on our ability to look out for our friends and not favor
现实是，作为美国，我们应该始终站出来，作为一个维护国际规则和规范的领导者，作为一个展现力量的领导者，理解我们在世界各地的联盟依赖于我们照顾朋友而不是偏袒
our enemies because you adore strongmen instead of caring about democracy.
我们的敌人，因为您崇拜强人而不关心民主。
And that is very much what is at stake here.
这正是我们所面临的风险。
The president of the United States is commander in chief, and the American people have a right to rely
美国总统是三军统帅，美国人民有权依赖
on a president who understands the significance of America's role and responsibility in terms of ensuring that there is stability and ensuring we stand up for our principles and not sell them for the benefit of personal flattery.
一个理解美国角色和责任重要性的总统，以确保稳定并确保我们捍卫我们的原则，而不是为了个人的奉承而出卖它们。
We've talked about Ukraine and Vladimir Putin.
我们谈到了乌克兰和弗拉基米尔·普京。
I do want to talk about Afghanistan.
我确实想谈谈阿富汗。
It came up in the first hour of this debate.
这在辩论的第一小时提到过。
I want to move on to Afghanistan.
我想转到阿富汗。
Trump did the most amazing thing I've ever seen.
特朗普做了我见过的最惊人的事情。
He got these countries, the 28 countries at the time, to pay up.
他让当时的28个国家付款。
He said, I've never seen.
他说，我从未见过。
He's the head of NATO.
他是北约的领导人。
He said, I've never seen.
他说，我从未见过。
For years, we were paying almost all of NATO.
多年来，我们几乎支付了所有北约的费用。
We were being ripped off by European nations, both on trade and on NATO.
我们被欧洲国家在贸易和北约上剥削。
I got them to pay up by saying one of the statements you made before, if you don't pay, we're not going to protect you.
我通过说您之前提到的那句话让他们付款，如果你不付款，我们就不会保护你。
Otherwise, we would have never gotten it.
否则，我们根本无法做到这一点。
He said it was one of the most incredible jobs that he's ever seen done.
他说这是他见过的最令人难以置信的工作之一。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I want to turn to Afghanistan.
我想谈谈阿富汗。
It came up in the first hour of the debate, and we witnessed a poignant moment today on Capitol Hill honoring the soldiers who died in the chaotic withdrawal from Afghanistan.
在辩论的第一个小时，这个话题被提及，我们今天在国会山见证了一个感人的时刻，缅怀在阿富汗混乱撤军中阵亡的士兵。
I do want to ask the vice president, do you believe you bear any responsibility in the way that withdrawal played out?
我确实想问副总统，您是否认为您在撤军的方式上承担任何责任？
Well, I will tell you, I agreed with President Biden's decision to pull out of Afghanistan.
嗯，我告诉你，我同意拜登总统撤出阿富汗的决定。
Four presidents said they would, and Joe Biden did.
四位总统曾表示他们会这样做，而乔·拜登做到了。
And as a result, America's taxpayers are not paying the $300 million a day we were paying for that endless war.
因此，美国纳税人不再支付我们为这场无休止的战争每天300万美元的费用。
And as of today, there is not one member of the United States military who is in active duty in a combat zone in any war zone around the world the first time this century.
截至今天，没有一名美国军人处于战斗状态，活跃于世界任何战区，这是本世纪的第一次。
But let's understand how we got to where we are.
但让我们理解我们是如何走到今天的。
Donald Trump, when he was president, negotiated one of the weakest deals you can imagine.
唐纳德·特朗普担任总统时，谈判了一个你无法想象的最弱的协议。
He calls himself a dealmaker.
他自称是一个交易者。
Even his national security adviser said it was a weak, terrible deal.
甚至他的国家安全顾问也表示这是一个弱而糟糕的协议。
And here's how it went down.
事情是这样发展的。
He bypassed the Afghan government.
他绕过了阿富汗政府。
He negotiated directly with a terrorist organization called the Taliban.
他直接与一个名为塔利班的恐怖组织进行谈判。
The negotiation involved the Taliban getting 5,000 terrorists, Taliban terrorists, released.
谈判涉及释放5000名塔利班恐怖分子。
And get this, no get this, and the president at the time invited the Taliban to Camp David.
而且，听着，没错，时任总统邀请塔利班来到戴维营。
a place of storied significance for us as Americans, a place where we honor the importance of American diplomacy, where we invite and receive respected world leaders, and this
这是对我们美国人来说具有历史意义的地方，一个我们尊重美国外交重要性的地方，我们在这里邀请并接待受尊敬的世界领导人，而这位
former President, as President, invited them to Camp David because he does not, again, appreciate the role and responsibility of the President of the United States to be Commander-in-Chief with a level of respect.
前总统，作为总统，邀请他们到戴维营，因为他再次不理解美国总统作为总司令的角色和责任，缺乏应有的尊重。
And this gets back to the point of how he has consistently disparaged and demeaned members of our military, fallen soldiers, and the work that we must do to uphold the strength
这又回到了他如何一贯贬低和轻视我们的军人、阵亡士兵，以及我们必须做的工作，以维护
and the respect of the United States of America around the world.
美国在世界范围内的力量和尊重。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢。
President Trump, your response to her saying that you began the negotiations with the Taliban?
特朗普总统，您对此回应她说您开始与塔利班谈判的看法是什么？
If you take a look at that period of time, the Taliban was killing our soldiers, a lot of them, with snipers.
如果你看看那个时期，塔利班正在用狙击手杀害我们的士兵，很多士兵。
And I got involved with the Taliban because the Taliban was doing the killing.
我参与与塔利班的谈判是因为塔利班在进行杀戮。
That's the fighting force within Afghanistan.
他们是阿富汗境内的战斗力量。
They don't bother doing that because, you know, they deal with the wrong people all the time.
他们并不愿意这样做，因为你知道，他们总是和错误的人打交道。
But I got involved.
但我参与了。
And Abdul is the head of the Taliban.
阿卜杜勒是塔利班的头目。
He is still the head of the Taliban.
他仍然是塔利班的头目。
And I told Abdul, don't do it anymore.
我告诉阿卜杜勒，不要再这样做了。
You do it anymore, you're going to have problems.
如果你再这样做，你会有麻烦。
And he said, why do you send me a picture of my house?
他说，为什么你给我发了一张我家照片？
I said, you're going to have to figure that out, Abdul.
我说，你得自己想办法，阿卜杜勒。
And for 18 months, we had nobody killed.
在18个月里，我们没有人被杀。
We did have an agreement negotiated by Mike Pompeo.
我们确实有一个由迈克·蓬佩奥谈判的协议。
It was a very good agreement.
这是一个非常好的协议。
The reason it was good, it was we were getting out.
之所以好，是因为我们要撤出。
We would have been out faster than them, but we wouldn't have lost the soldiers.
我们本可以比他们更快撤出，但我们不会失去士兵。
We wouldn't have left many Americans behind.
我们不会留下很多美国人。
We wouldn't have left.
我们不会留下。
$85 billion worth of brand-new beautiful military equipment behind and just to finish they Blew it the agreement said you have to do this this this this this and they didn't do it They didn't do it the agreement was
价值850亿美元的全新美丽军事装备，最后他们毁掉了这一切，协议说你必须这样、那样，而他们没有做到，他们没有做到，协议是
was terminated by us because they didn't do what they were supposed to do.
因为他们没有履行应尽的责任而被我们终止的。
And these people did the worst withdrawal and, in my opinion, the most embarrassing moment in the history of our country.
这些人进行了最糟糕的撤退，在我看来，这是我们国家历史上最尴尬的时刻。
And by the way, that's why Russia attacked Ukraine, because they saw how incompetent she and her boss are.
顺便说一句，这就是俄罗斯攻击乌克兰的原因，因为他们看到了她和她的老板是多么无能。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢。
I want to move on now to race and politics in this country.
我想现在转向这个国家的种族和政治问题。
Mr. President, you recently said of Vice President Harris, quote, I didn't know she was black until a number of years ago when she happened to turn black and now she wants to be known as black.
总统先生，您最近说过副总统哈里斯，引用，“我不知道她是黑人，直到几年前她恰好变成黑人，现在她想被称为黑人。”
I want to ask a bigger picture question here tonight.
我今晚想问一个更大的问题。
Why do you believe it's appropriate to weigh in on the racial identity of your opponent?
您认为为什么有必要对对手的种族身份发表看法？
I don't and I don't care.
我不这样认为，我也不在乎。
I don't care what she is.
我不在乎她是什么。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
uh, you make a big deal out of something, I couldn't care less.
呃，你把一件事搞得很大，我根本不在乎。
Whatever she wants to be is okay with me.
她想成为什么都可以。
But those were your words.
但那是你的话。
So I don't know.
所以我不知道。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I mean, all I can say is I read where she was not black that she put out and I'll say that.
我的意思是，我只想说我看到她说她不是黑人，我会这么说。
And then I read that she was black and that's okay.
然后我又看到她说她是黑人，这没问题。
Either one was okay with me.
对我来说，这两种说法都可以。
That's up to her.
这由她决定。
Vice President Harris, your thoughts on this?
哈里斯副总统，您对此有何看法？
I think it's – I mean, honestly, I think it's a tragedy that we have someone who wants to be president who has consistently over the course of his career attempted to use race to divide the American people.
我认为这——我真的认为这是一个悲剧，我们有一个想要成为总统的人，在他职业生涯的过程中，始终试图利用种族来分裂美国人民。
You know, I do believe that the vast majority of us know that we have so much more in common than what separates us, and we don't want this kind of approach that is just constantly trying to divide us, and especially by race.
您知道，我确实相信绝大多数人都知道，我们有更多的共同点而非分隔我们的差异，我们不想要这种不断试图分裂我们的方式，尤其是通过种族。
And let's remember how Donald Trump started.
让我们回顾一下唐纳德·特朗普是如何开始的。
He was a land—he owned land, he owned buildings, and he was investigated because he refused to rent.
他拥有土地，他拥有建筑物，并且因为拒绝向黑人家庭出租而受到调查。
property to black families.
让我们记住，这就是那个在《纽约时报》上刊登整版广告，呼吁处决五名无辜的年轻黑人和拉丁裔男孩的同一个人，中央公园五人。
Let's remember, this is the same individual who took out a full page ad in the New York Times calling for the execution of five young black and Latino boys who were innocent, the Central Park Five.
他刊登了整版广告，呼吁处决他们。
took out a full-page ad calling for their execution.
这个人就是散布关于美国第一位黑人总统的虚假言论的同一个人。
This is the same individual who spread birther lies about the first black president of the United States.
我认为美国人民希望得到更好的，希望有一个理解我们的人，正如我所做的，我游历我们的国家。
And I think the American people want better than that, want better than this, want someone who understands, as I do, I travel our country.
我们在彼此身上看到了朋友。
We see in each other a friend.
我们在彼此身上看到了邻居。
We see in each other a neighbor.
我们不希望有一个领导者不断试图让美国人互相指责。
We don't want a leader who is constantly trying to have Americans point their fingers at each other.
我经常与人会面，他们告诉我
I meet with people all the time who tell me
我们能不能就如何投资于美国人民的愿望、雄心和梦想进行讨论？
Can we please just have discourse about how we're going to invest in the aspirations and the ambitions and the dreams of the American people?
无论一个人的肤色或他们祖母说的语言如何，我们都有相同的梦想和愿望，希望有一位投资于这些梦想的总统，而不是仇恨和分裂。
Knowing that regardless of people's color or the language their grandmother speaks, we all have the same dreams and aspirations and want a president who invests in those, not in hate and division.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢您。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
林赛？
Lindsey?
特朗普总统，这是您第三次
President Trump, this is now your third time
这是我们国家历史上最具分裂性的总统任期。
This is the most divisive presidency in the history of our country.
从未有过这样的情况。
There's never been anything like it.
他们正在摧毁我们的国家，而他们提出的事情就像她刚才所说的那样。
They're destroying our country, and they come up with things like what she just said.
回顾许多年前，许多人，包括布隆伯格市长，都同意我对中央公园五人的看法，他们承认，他们说，他们认罪。
Going back many, many years, when a lot of people, including Mayor Bloomberg, agreed with me on the Central Park Five, they admitted, they said, they pled guilty.
我说，好吧，如果他们认罪，他们确实伤害了一个人，最终杀了一个人。
And I said, well, if they pled guilty, they'd badly hurt a person, killed a person, ultimately.
这就是我所说的。
And if they pled guilty, then they pled.
如果他们认罪，那就是认罪。
We're not guilty.
我们没有罪。
But this is a person that has to stretch back years, 40, 50 years ago, because there's nothing now.
但这是一个必须追溯到40年、50年前的人，因为现在没有任何东西。
I built one of the greatest economies in the history of the world, and I'm going to build it again.
我建立了历史上最伟大的经济之一，我将再次建立它。
It's going to be bigger, better and stronger.
它将会更大、更好、更强。
But they're destroying our economy.
但他们正在摧毁我们的经济。
They have no idea what a good economy is.
他们根本不知道什么是好的经济。
Their oil policies, every single policy.
他们的石油政策，每一项政策。
And remember this.
记住这一点。
She is Biden.
她就是拜登。
You know, she's trying to get away from Biden.
你知道，她试图与拜登划清界限。
I don't know the gentleman, she says.
她说她不认识那位先生。
She is Biden.
她就是拜登。
The worst inflation we've ever had.
我们经历过的最糟糕的通货膨胀。
A horrible economy because inflation has made it so bad.
因为通货膨胀变得如此严重，导致经济非常糟糕。
And she can't get away with that.
而她无法逃避这一点。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Your time is up.
你的时间到了。
I want to respond to that, though.
不过，我想对此做个回应。
I want to just respond briefly.
我想简单回应一下。
Clearly, I am not Joe Biden, and I am certainly not Donald Trump.
显然，我不是乔·拜登，我也绝对不是唐纳德·特朗普。
And what I do offer is a new generation of leadership for our country, one who believes in what is possible, one who brings a sense of optimism about what we can do instead of always disparaging the American people.
我所提供的是我们国家新一代的领导力，相信可能性的人，带来对我们能做什么的乐观态度，而不是总是贬低美国人民。
I believe in what we can do to
我相信我们能做的事情
to strengthen our small businesses, which is why I have a plan.
来加强我们的中小企业，这就是我有计划的原因。
Let's talk about our plans and let's compare the plans.
让我们谈谈我们的计划，并比较一下计划。
I have a plan to give startup businesses $50,000 tax deduction
我有一个计划，为初创企业提供5万美元的税收减免
to pursue their ambitions, their innovation, their ideas, their hard work.
以追求他们的抱负、创新、想法和辛勤工作。
I have a plan, $6,000 for young families for the first year of your child's life to help you in that most critical stage of your child's development.
我有一个计划，为年轻家庭提供6000美元，以帮助你们度过孩子生命的第一年，这是孩子成长中最关键的阶段。
I have a plan.
我有一个计划。
That is about allowing people to be able to pursue what has been fleeting in terms of the American dream by offering a help with down payment of $25,000 down payment assistance for first-time home buyers.
这是关于让人们能够追求曾经稍纵即逝的美国梦，提供2.5万美元的首付援助，帮助首次购房者。
That's the kind of conversation, I believe, David, that people really want tonight, as opposed to a conversation that is constantly about belittling and name-calling.
我相信，戴维，这才是人们今晚真正想要的对话，而不是不断贬低和辱骂的对话。
Let's turn the page and move forward.
让我们翻过这一页，向前迈进。
President Trump, we have to move on.
特朗普总统，我们必须继续讨论其他问题。
She has a plan to defund the police.
她有一个削减警察经费的计划。
She has a plan to confiscate everybody's gun.
她有一个没收每个人枪支的计划。
President Trump, we do have to move on to other issues.
特朗普总统，我们确实需要转向其他问题。
in Pennsylvania or anywhere else.
在宾夕法尼亚州或其他任何地方。
That's what her plan is until just recently.
这就是她的计划，直到最近为止。
The former president has said something twice that I need to respond to.
前总统说过两次我需要回应的话。
I just need to respond one time to what he has said multiple times.
我只需要对他多次提到的内容回应一次。
President Trump, this is now your third time running for president.
特朗普总统，这是您第三次竞选总统。
You have long vowed to repeal and replace the Affordable Care Act, also known as Obamacare.
您早就发誓要废除并取代《平价医疗法案》，也就是奥巴马医保。
You have failed to accomplish that.
您未能实现这个目标。
You now say you're going to keep Obamacare, quote, unless we can do something much better.
您现在说您将保留奥巴马医保，引用“除非我们能做得更好”。
Last month, you said, quote, we're working on it.
上个月，您说，引用“我们正在努力”。
So tonight, nine years after you first started running, do you have a plan and can you tell us what it is?
所以今晚，在您首次开始竞选的九年后，您有计划吗？能告诉我们是什么吗？
Obamacare was lousy health care, always was.
奥巴马医保是一种糟糕的医疗保健，始终如此。
It's not very good today.
今天的情况也不佳。
And what I said, that if we come up with something and we are working on things, we're going to do it and we're going to replace it.
我所说的是，如果我们想出什么解决方案，并且我们正在努力，我们会做到并取而代之。
But remember this.
但请记住这一点。
I inherited Obamacare because Democrats wouldn't change it.
我继承了奥巴马医保，因为民主党人不愿意改变它。
They wouldn't vote for it.
他们不愿意投票支持。
They were unanimous.
他们是一致反对的。
They wouldn't vote to change it.
他们不愿意投票改变它。
If they would have done that, we would have had a much better plan than Obamacare.
如果他们那样做的话，我们会有比奥巴马医保更好的计划。
But the Democrats came up, they wouldn't vote for it.
但民主党人提出了，他们不愿意投票支持。
I had a choice to make when I was president.
当我担任总统时，我面临一个选择。
Do I save it and make it as good as it can be, never going to be great, or do I let it rot?
我是否应该保留它并尽可能地改进它，永远不会变得伟大，还是让我它腐烂？
And I felt I had an obligation, even though politically it would have been good to just let it rot and let it go away.
我觉得我有责任，尽管从政治上讲，放任它腐烂让它消失会更好。
I decided, and I told my people, the top people, and they're very good people.
我做出了决定，我告诉我的团队，顶尖的人，他们都是非常优秀的人。
I have a lot of good people in this, that administration.
我在这个政府中有很多好人。
We read about the bad ones.
我们听说过坏人。
We had some real bad ones too, and so do they.
我们也有一些真正的坏人，他们也有。
They have really bad ones.
他们有非常坏的人。
The difference is they don't get rid of them.
区别在于他们不会把这些人处理掉。
But let me just
但让我来解释一下。
explain.
我面临一个选择。
I had a choice to make.
我是否要拯救它，让它尽可能好？
Do I save it and make it as good as it can be?
还是让我让它腐烂？
Or do I let it rot?
我拯救了它。
And I saved it.
我做了正确的事。
I did the right thing.
但它仍然不会变得伟大，而且对人们来说太昂贵了。
But it's still never going to be great, and it's too expensive for people.
我们将要做的是，我们正在考虑不同的计划。
And what we will do is we're looking at different plans.
如果我们能提出一个将使我们的人民、我们的民众花费更少的钱，并且提供比《平价医疗法案》更好的医疗保健，那么我绝对会这样做。
If we can come up with a plan that's going to cost
但在那之前，我会尽可能好的运营它。
our people, our population, less money, and be better healthcare than Obamacare, then I would absolutely do it.
所以，简单地说，是或不是，你仍然没有计划？
But until then, I'd run it as good as it can be run.
我有一些计划的概念。
So, just a yes or no, you still do not have a plan?
我现在不是总统。
I have concepts of a plan.
但如果我们提出一些东西。
I'm not president right now.
我只会在我们提出更好且更便宜的方案时做出改变。
But if
而且我们有一些概念和选择可以做到这一点。
We come up with something.
而且你们将在不久的将来听到关于它的消息。
I would only change it if we come up with something that's better and less expensive.
哈里斯副总统，在2017年，你支持伯尼·桑德斯的提案，取消私人保险并创建一个政府主导的医疗保健系统。
And there are concepts and options we have to do that.
两年后，你提出了一个包括私人保险选项的计划。
And you'll be hearing about it in the not-too-distant future.
你今天的计划是什么？
Vice President Harris, in 2017, you supported Bernie Sanders' proposal to do away with private insurance and create a government-run healthcare system.
首先，我绝对支持私人医疗保健选项，在过去四年担任副总统期间也是如此，但我们需要做的是维护和发展《平价医疗法案》。
Two years later, you proposed a plan that included a private insurance option.
但是我会提到这一点，林赛，我只需要对前总统提到的一个观点做出回应。
What is your plan today?
我想我们需要继续努力。
Well, first of all, I absolutely support, and over the last four years as vice president, private healthcare options, but what we need to do is maintain and grow the Affordable Care Act.
我们要确保每个人都能获得负担得起的医疗保健。
But I'll get to that, Lindsay, I just need to respond to a previous point that the former president has made.
这是我们必须继续追求的目标。
I've made very clear my position on fracking, and then this business about taking everyone's guns away.
我已经非常明确地表明了我对压裂的立场，以及关于夺走每个人的枪支的说法。
Tim Walz and I are both gun owners.
蒂姆·沃兹和我都是持枪者。
We're not taking anybody's guns away, so stop with the continuous lying about this stuff.
我们不会夺走任何人的枪，所以请停止对这些事情的持续撒谎。
As it relates to the Affordable Care Act, understand, just look at the history to know where people stand.
关于《平价医疗法案》，要理解，只需看看历史就知道人们的立场。
When Donald Trump was president, 60 times he tried to get rid of the Affordable Care Act.
当唐纳德·特朗普担任总统时，他试图60次废除《平价医疗法案》。
60 times.
60次。
I was a senator at the time when, I will never forget the early morning hours when it was up for a vote in the United States Senate.
当时我是一名参议员，我永远不会忘记在美国参议院投票的清晨时光。
And the late, great John McCain, who you have disparaged,
已故伟大的约翰·麦凯恩，你曾贬低他，
as being, you don't like him, you said, at the time, because he got caught.
因为你当时说你不喜欢他，因为他被抓住了。
He was an American hero.
他是一位美国英雄。
The late, great John McCain, I will never forget that night, walked onto the Senate floor and said, no you don't.
已故伟大的约翰·麦凯恩，我永远不会忘记那晚，他走进参议院说，不，你不能。
No you don't.
不，你不能。
No, you don't get rid of the Affordable Care Act.
不，你不能废除《平价医疗法案》。
You have no plan.
你没有计划。
And what the Affordable Care Act has done is eliminate the ability of insurance companies to deny people with pre-existing conditions.
而《平价医疗法案》所做的就是消除了保险公司拒绝有既往病史的人投保的能力。
I don't have to tell the people watching tonight, you remember what that was like?
我不需要告诉今晚收看的人，你们还记得那是什么样子吗？
Remember when an insurance company could deny
还记得当保险公司可以拒绝
if a child had asthma, if someone was a breast cancer survivor, if a grandparent had diabetes.
如果一个孩子有哮喘，某人是乳腺癌幸存者，或者祖父母有糖尿病吗？
And thankfully, as I've been vice president and we over the last four years have strengthened the Affordable Care Act, we have allowed for the first time Medicare to negotiate drug prices on behalf of you, the American people.
值得庆幸的是，作为副总统的我，在过去四年里加强了《平价医疗法案》，我们首次允许医疗保险为你们，美国人民，谈判药品价格。
Donald Trump said he was going to allow Medicare to negotiate
唐纳德·特朗普说他要允许医疗保险谈判
drug prices?
药品价格？
He never did.
他从未这样做。
We did.
我们做到了。
And now we have capped the cost of insulin at $35 a month.
现在我们将胰岛素的费用上限设定为每月35美元。
Since I've been vice president, we have capped the cost of prescription medication for seniors at $2,000 a year.
自从我担任副总统以来，我们将老年人的处方药费用上限设定为每年2000美元。
And when I am president, we will do that for all people, understanding that the value I bring to this
当我成为总统时，我们将为所有人做到这一点，理解我所带来的价值
is that access to health care should be a right and not just a privilege of those who can afford it.
是医疗保健的获得应该是权利，而不仅仅是那些能够负担得起的人的特权。
And the plan has to be to strengthen the Affordable Care Act, not get rid of it, practice prologue in terms of where Donald Trump stands on that.
计划必须是加强《平价医疗法案》，而不是废除它，关于唐纳德·特朗普在这方面的立场。
I want to move to an issue that's important for a lot of... You made a mistake.
我想转向一个对很多人来说很重要的问题……你犯了一个错误。
At number one, John McCain fought Obamacare for 10 years.
首先，约翰·麦凯恩为奥巴马医改斗争了十年。
But it wasn't only him.
但不仅仅是他一个人。
It were all of the Democrats that kept it going.
所有民主党人都在继续这个。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
We can do much better than Obamacare, much less money.
我们可以做得比《平价医疗法案》更好，花更少的钱。
But she won't improve private insurance for people, private medical insurance.
但她不会改善人们的私人医疗保险。
That's another thing she doesn't want to get.
这也是她不想做的另一件事。
People are paying privately for insurance that have worked hard and made money and they want to have private.
那些努力工作并赚了钱的人正在为私人保险付费，他们想要私人保险。
She wants everybody to be on government insurance where you wait.
她希望每个人都在政府的保险下，而你得等待。
Six months for an operation that you need immediately.
等待六个月才能进行你急需的手术。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢。
We have another issue that we'd like to get to that's important for a number of Americans, in particular younger voters, and that's climate change.
我们还有一个问题想要讨论，这对许多美国人，特别是年轻选民来说很重要，那就是气候变化。
President Trump, with regard to the environment, you say that we have to have clean air and clean water.
特朗普总统，关于环境，您说我们必须拥有清洁的空气和水。
Vice President Harris, you call climate change an existential threat.
哈里斯副总统，您称气候变化为生存威胁。
The question to you both tonight is what would you do to fight climate change?
今晚的问题是，你们会怎么做来应对气候变化？
And Vice President Harris, we'll start with you.
哈里斯副总统，我们从您开始。
One minute for you each.
你们各有一分钟。
Well, the former president had said that climate change is a hoax.
前总统曾说气候变化是个骗局。
And what we know is that it is very real.
而我们知道它是非常真实的。
You ask anyone who lives in a state who has experienced these extreme weather occurrences, who now is either being denied home insurance or is being jacked up, you ask anybody who has been the victim of what that means in terms of losing their home, having nowhere to go, we know that we can actually deal with this issue.
你问任何一个经历过极端天气事件的州的人，他们现在要么被拒绝家庭保险，要么保险费被抬高，问问任何一个失去家园、无处可去的人，我们知道我们实际上可以解决这个问题。
The young people of America care deeply about this issue.
美国的年轻人对此问题非常关心。
And I am proud that as vice president over the last four years, we have invested a trillion dollars in a clean energy economy while we have also increased domestic gas production to historic levels.
我为作为副总统在过去四年里投资了一万亿美元于清洁能源经济而感到自豪，同时我们也将国内天然气生产提高到了历史水平。
We have created over 800,000 new manufacturing jobs while I have been vice president.
在我担任副总统期间，我们创造了超过80万个新的制造业岗位。
We have invested in clean energy to the point that we are opening up factories around the world.
我们在清洁能源上的投资使我们在全球范围内开设工厂。
Donald Trump said he was going to create manufacturing jobs.
唐纳德·特朗普曾说他会创造制造业岗位。
He lost manufacturing jobs.
他却失去了制造业岗位。
And I'm also proud to have the endorsement of the United Auto Workers and Sean Fain, who also know that part of building a clean energy economy includes investing in American-made products, American automobiles it includes.
我也很自豪得到美国汽车工人和肖恩·芬的支持，他们都知道，建设清洁能源经济的一部分包括投资于美国制造的产品，包括美国汽车。
growing what we can do around American manufacturing and opening up auto plants, not closing them like happened under Donald Trump.
这也包括扩大我们在美国制造业的能力和开设汽车工厂，而不是像唐纳德·特朗普执政期间那样关闭它们。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢。
That didn't happen under Donald Trump.
在唐纳德·特朗普执政期间并没有发生这种情况。
Let me just tell you, they lost 10,000 manufacturing jobs this last month.
让我告诉你，他们上个月失去了1万个制造业岗位。
It's going, they're all leaving.
情况正在变化，他们都在离开。
They're building big auto plants in Mexico, in many cases owned by China.
他们在墨西哥建造大型汽车工厂，许多情况下是中国拥有的。
They're building these massive plants and they think they're going to sell their cars into the United States because of these people.
他们正在建造这些巨大的工厂，并认为他们可以将汽车销售到美国，因为这些人。
What they have given to China is unbelievable, but we're not going to let that.
他们给中国的让步是不可思议的，但我们不会让这种情况继续。
We'll put tariffs on those cars so they can't come into our country because they will kill
我们会对这些汽车征收关税，以便它们无法进入我们的国家，因为它们会摧毁
the United Auto Workers and any auto worker, whether it's in Detroit or South Carolina or any other place, what they've done to business and manufacturing in this country is horrible.
美国汽车工人，无论是在底特律、南卡罗来纳州还是其他地方，他们对这个国家的商业和制造业造成的伤害是可怕的。
We have nothing because they refuse.
我们一无所有，因为他们拒绝。
You know, Biden doesn't go after people because supposedly China paid him millions of dollars.
你知道，拜登没有追究那些人，因为据说中国给了他数百万美元。
He's afraid to do it between him and his son.
他害怕在他和他儿子之间做这件事。
They get all this money from Ukraine.
他们从乌克兰获得了所有这些钱。
They get all this money from all of these different countries.
他们从这些不同的国家获得了所有这些资金。
And then you wonder, why is he so loyal to this one, that one, Ukraine, China?
然后你会想，为什么他对这个、那个、乌克兰、中国如此忠诚？
Why is he?
为什么？
Why did he get $3.5 million from the mayor of Moscow's wife?
为什么他从莫斯科市长的妻子那里获得了350万美元？
Why did he get — why did she pay him $3.5 million?
为什么她要给他350万美元？
This is a crooked administration, and they're selling our country down the tubes.
这是一个腐败的政府，他们正在将我们的国家卖掉。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢您。
Thank you.
谢谢。
We'll be right back with closing statements from both of our candidates, an historic night, this ABC News presidential debate from Philadelphia.
我们将很快回来，听取我们两位候选人的总结发言，这是一个历史性的夜晚，来自费城的ABC新闻总统辩论。
Back in a moment.
稍后回来。
The ABC News presidential debate will continue after this.
ABC新闻总统辩论将在此后继续。
Live from the National Constitution Center in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, here again, David Muir and Lindsay Davis.
来自宾夕法尼亚州费城的国家宪法中心，欢迎再次回到这里，David Muir 和 Lindsay Davis。
Welcome back tonight.
欢迎今晚的回归。
The time has come for closing statements.
时机已到，进行总结发言。
And Vice President Harris, we begin with you.
哈里斯副总统，我们从您开始。
So I think you've heard tonight two very different visions for our country, one that is focused on the future and the other that is focused on the past and an attempt to take us backward.
我认为今晚你听到了两个截然不同的国家愿景，一个专注于未来，另一个专注于过去，并试图让我们倒退。
But we're not going back.
但我们不会回去。
And I do believe that the American people know we all have so much more in common than what separates us.
我确实相信美国人民知道，我们有更多的共同点，而不是分开我们的东西。
And we can chart a new way forward.
我们可以开辟一条新的前进之路。
And a vision of that includes having a plan, understanding the aspirations, the dreams, the hopes, the ambition of the American people, which is why I intend to create
这个愿景包括拥有一个计划，理解美国人民的愿望、梦想、希望和雄心，这就是为什么我打算创造。
an opportunity economy, investing in small businesses, in new families, in what we can do around protecting seniors, what we can do that is about giving hardworking folks a break and bringing down the cost of living.
一个机会经济，投资于小企业，投资于新家庭，保护老年人的措施，帮助辛勤工作的人减轻负担，降低生活成本。
I believe in what we can do together that is about sustaining America's standing in the world and ensuring that we have the respect that we so rightly deserve, including respecting our military and ensuring we have the most lethal fighting force in the world.
我相信我们可以共同努力，维持美国在世界上的地位，确保我们获得应有的尊重，包括尊重我们的军队，确保我们拥有世界上最强大的作战力量。
I will be a president that will protect our fundamental rights and freedoms, including the right of a woman to make decisions about her own body and not have her government tell her what to do.
我将成为一个保护我们基本权利和自由的总统，包括女性对自己身体做决定的权利，而不是让政府来告诉她该怎么做。
I'll tell you, I started my career as a prosecutor.
我告诉你，我的职业生涯是从检察官开始的。
I was a DA, I was an Attorney General, a United States Senator, and now Vice President.
我曾是地区检察官，曾任检察长，还是美国参议员，现在是副总统。
I've only had one client, the people.
我只有一个客户，那就是人民。
And I'll tell you, as a prosecutor, I never asked a victim or a witness, are you a Republican or a Democrat?
作为检察官，我从来没有问过受害者或证人，你是共和党人还是民主党人？
The only thing I ever asked them, are you okay?
我唯一问过他们的就是，你还好吗？
And that's the kind of president we need right now, someone who cares about you and is not putting themselves first.
这就是我们现在需要的总统，关心你的人，而不是把自己放在第一位。
I intend to be a president for all Americans and focus on what we can do over the next 10 and 20 years to build back up our country by investing right now in you, the American people.
我打算成为所有美国人的总统，专注于我们在未来10年和20年里可以做的事情，通过现在投资于你们，美国人民，来重建我们的国家。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢。
President Trump?
特朗普总统？
So she just started by saying she's going to do this, she's going to do that, she's going to do all these wonderful things.
她刚才说她要做这个，要做那个，要做所有这些美好的事情。
Why hasn't she done it?
那么她为什么不去做呢？
She's been there for three and a half years.
她已经在那里三年半了。
They've had three and a half years to fix the border.
他们已经有三年半的时间来解决边境问题。
They've had three and a half years to
他们已经有三年半的时间来
create jobs, and all the things we talked about.
创造就业机会，以及我们谈到的所有事情。
Why hasn't she done it?
她为什么不去做呢？
She should leave right now, go down to that beautiful White House, go to the Capitol, get everyone together and do the things you want to do.
她应该现在就离开，去那座美丽的白宫，去国会，召集大家一起做她想做的事情。
But you haven't done it, and you won't do it, because you believe in things that the American people don't believe in.
但是你没有去做，你也不会去做，因为你相信的事情是美国人民不相信的。
You believe in things like
你相信的事情像是
We're not going to frack.
我们不会进行水力压裂。
We're not going to take fossil fuel.
我们不会利用化石燃料。
We're not going to do things that are going to make this country strong, whether you like it or not.
我们不会做那些会让这个国家强大的事情，无论你喜欢与否。
Germany tried that.
德国尝试过那样做。
And within one year, they were back to building normal energy plants.
在一年内，他们又开始建设正常的能源厂。
We're not ready for it.
我们还没有准备好。
We can't sacrifice our country for the sake of bad vision.
我们不能为了糟糕的愿景而牺牲我们的国家。
But I just ask one simple question.
但我只问一个简单的问题。
Why didn't she do it?
她为什么不这样做？
We're a failing nation.
我们是一个失败的国家。
We're a nation that's in serious decline.
我们是一个严重衰退的国家。
We're being laughed at all over the world.
我们在全世界都被嘲笑。
All over the world, they laugh.
全世界都在嘲笑我们。
I know the leaders very well.
我非常了解这些领导人。
They're coming to see me.
他们来见我。
They call me.
他们给我打电话。
We're laughed at all over the world.
我们在全世界都被嘲笑。
They don't understand what happened to us as a nation.
他们不明白我们国家发生了什么。
We're not a leader.
我们不是领导者。
We don't have any idea what's going on.
我们对发生的事情一无所知。
We have wars going on in the Middle East.
我们在中东有战争。
We have wars going on with Russia and Ukraine.
我们与俄罗斯和乌克兰之间也有冲突。
We're going to end up in a third world war and it'll be a war like no other because of nuclear weapons, the power of weaponry.
我们将最终陷入第三次世界大战，那将是一场前所未有的战争，因为核武器和武器的威力。
I rebuilt our entire military.
我重建了我们整个军事力量。
She gave a lot of it away to the Taliban.
她把很多武器交给了塔利班。
She gave it to Afghanistan.
她把它们给了阿富汗。
What these people have done to our country and maybe toughest of all is allowing millions of
这些人对我们国家所做的事情，或许最严重的是允许数百万
people to come into our country.
人进入我们的国家。
Many of them are criminals, and they're destroying our country.
他们中的许多人是罪犯，他们正在摧毁我们的国家。
The worst president, the worst vice president in the history of our country.
历史上最糟糕的总统，最糟糕的副总统。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢您。
And that is our ABC News presidential debate from here in Philadelphia at the National Constitution Center.
这就是我们在费城国家宪法中心的ABC新闻总统辩论。
I'm Lindsay Davis.
我是林赛·戴维斯。
And I'm David Muir.
我是大卫·穆尔。
Thank you for watching here in the U.S.
感谢您在美国和
and all over the world and from all of us here at ABC News.
全世界收看我们ABC新闻的节目。
Good night.
晚安。
Thanks for watching.
感谢观看。
Stay updated about breaking news and top stories on the NBC News app or follow us on social media.
通过NBC新闻应用程序获取最新的突发新闻和热门故事，或在社交媒体上关注我们。